<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How to Live in Paradise</title>
    <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/</link>
    <description>Recent content on How to Live in Paradise</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/administrators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/administrators/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-administer-administrators:895aab9d9861ff39e49a42699223346a&#34;&gt;How to Administer Administrators&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;A href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/u/0/photos/114975801512009922265/albums/5695296030918759809/5695296145666543714?pid=5695296145666543714&amp;oid=114975801512009922265&#34;&gt;
&lt;img
src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-3WJBrHRf9TY/TwnBq2UbEGI/AAAAAAAAAro/lU-REVB45do/w1654-h980-no/IMG_3008.jpg&#34;
class=&#34;rightbar&#34; alt=&#34;Prohibited items at Taj Mahal&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/u/0/photos/114975801512009922265/albums/5695296030918759809/5695299273306513154?pid=5695299273306513154&amp;oid=114975801512009922265&#34;&gt;
&lt;img
src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-inC3NcTpolw/TwnEg5r5nwI/AAAAAAAAAtg/kC0U0rHpr8U/w1326-h1110-no/IMG_3083.jpg&#34;
alt=&#34;Entitlements&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/conventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/conventions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://homepages.cs.ncl.ac.uk/brian.randell/NATO/nato1969.PDF&#34;&gt;http://homepages.cs.ncl.ac.uk/brian.randell/NATO/nato1969.PDF&lt;/a&gt;
Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s list on page 10!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ira Glass quote on creativity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human Creativity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve occasionally been asked by students if I think computers will ever
be able to replicate &amp;ldquo;human creativity&amp;rdquo;.  My answer is that no, my
definition, because our definition of &amp;ldquo;human creativity&amp;rdquo; is those things
that computers can&amp;rsquo;t yet do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playing world class chess was once thought to require some of the
highest human intelligence and crative abilities; then IBM built a
computer that could beat the world&amp;rsquo;s best human chess players just by
having an enormous database of previous games and enough computational
power to search billions of positions, and a few clever algorithmic
tricks to prune the search tree effectively.  Writing music seems like
an essentially creative human activity, but software can now compose
music than even experts have a hard time distinguishing from Mozart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until recently, poker seemed like a last bastion where humanity might
hold an advantage, but that appears to be short-lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I think we can still recognize&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;being &amp;ldquo;creative&amp;rdquo;, whether in research, teaching, or
administrating,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the close mode, I mean the mode that we are in most of the time when we&amp;rsquo;re at work&amp;hellip;. Its an active, slightly anxious mode,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a little tension in it, not much humor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By contract the open mode, is relaxed, expansive, less purposeful, in which we&amp;rsquo;re probably more con&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;more playful&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Because we&amp;rsquo;re not under pressure to get a specific thing done quickly,
we can play, and that is what allows our natural creativity to surface.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AU5x1Ea7NjQ&amp;amp;t=7m36s&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AU5x1Ea7NjQ&amp;amp;t=7m36s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/advising/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/advising/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://scienceblogs.com/thescian/2008/03/11/what-are-worthwhile-problems-f/&#34;&gt;http://scienceblogs.com/thescian/2008/03/11/what-are-worthwhile-problems-f/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;
You met me at the peak of my career when I seemed to you to be concerned with problems close to the gods. But at the same time I had another Ph.D. Student (Albert Hibbs) was on how it is that the winds build up waves blowing over water in the sea. I accepted him as a student because he came to me with the problem he wanted to solve. With you I made a mistake, I gave you the problem instead of letting you find your own; and left you with a wrong idea of what is interesting or pleasant or important to work on (namely those problems you see you may do something about). I am sorry, excuse me. I hope by this letter to correct it a little.
&amp;hellip;
No problem is too small or too trivial if we can really do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You say you are a nameless man. You are not to your wife and to your child. You will not long remain so to your immediate colleagues if you can answer their simple questions when they come into your office. You are not nameless to me. Do not remain nameless to yourself – it is too sad a way to be. now your place in the world and evaluate yourself fairly, not in terms of your naïve ideals of your own youth, nor in terms of what you erroneously imagine your teacher’s ideals are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-advise:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How to Advise&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three main different types of advising you&amp;rsquo;ll do as a faculty
member: &lt;em&gt;academic&lt;/em&gt; advising, &lt;em&gt;ad hoc&lt;/em&gt; advising, and &lt;em&gt;researh&lt;/em&gt; advising.
These are very different, but doing one well can sometimes lead to
opportunities to do the next type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-be-helpful-academic-advising:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How to Be Helpful (&lt;em&gt;Academic&lt;/em&gt; Advising)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started at UVa, all new faculty in the Engineering School were
required (footnote: this is before I realized faculty cannot actually be
&amp;ldquo;required&amp;rdquo; to do anything, and any activity which administrators label
as &amp;ldquo;mandatory&amp;rdquo; is a good signal that the people doing it realize no one
would go to it &amp;ldquo;voluntarily&amp;rdquo;, so it is almost certainly a waste of your
time, so I mindlessly went to it) to attend a two-hour long meeting
about advising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-be-accessible-ad-hoc-advising:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How to Be Accessible (&lt;em&gt;Ad hoc&lt;/em&gt; Advising)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad hoc&lt;/em&gt; advising is one of the most important (and hardest) things you
can do as a faculty member, even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t show up anywhere on your
school&amp;rsquo;s mandated annual report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most college students are at a stage in their lives when nearly all of their interactions so far with adults (other than hopefully their parents) have been of the &lt;em&gt;command and control&lt;/em&gt; variety.  Adults tell them what to do, and if they do it satisfactorily they are rewarded (or at least avoid punishment).&lt;br /&gt;
Entering college students naturally find the notion of talking with a professor intimidating - by closest frame of reference, you a less-well dressed, better paid and more powerful version of their high school teachers except instead of inhabiting in the same classrooms as they do, you occasionally stop by a well-hidden office somewhere in another building.  So, it takes some effort to come across as accessible enough so students will talk with you about anything important.    Until becoming professors, most people who do spent the majority of their life being the intimidee rather than the intimidator (i.e., not to stereotype, but with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~robins/moments.html#workout&#34;&gt;rare exceptions&lt;/a&gt;, very few of the professors I know are physically intimidating) so the hard part is to gain the perspective to realize most students find the thought of talking with you terrifying.  Once you see that, there are various ways to come Òde-intiminizeÓ yourself, most of which are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs200-spring2003/poolside/&#34;&gt;fun&lt;/a&gt; and worthwhile for their own sake.  (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~weimer/weimer-415-sp07-fencing.jpg&#34;&gt;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~weimer/weimer-415-sp07-fencing.jpg&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you succeed in tricking students into finding you accessible,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-advising:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;Research Advising&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How an Why to Advise Research Students&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Klinsi quote ÒI felt proudÓ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to ÒMarryÓ Your Students
Do you, wise advisor, take this student to be your hopeful and eager advisee,
To fund and to guide,
Through setbacks and breakthroughs,
So long as you still believe she has a chance to become an independent researcher.
(I do)
Do you, eager student, take this advisor to be your &amp;mdash; - - &amp;ndash; mentor,
 To work and to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-teach:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How to Teach&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the ridiculously poor quality and low expectations of nearly all university teaching, following two simple rules will be enough to make you an exceptional teacher:
1. &lt;strong&gt;Respect your studentsÕ time.&lt;/strong&gt;  Both the time they choose to spend in your classroom when they could otherwise be catching up on much-needed sleep, and the time they spend on any assignments you require.  Remember most university students still have the high school mentality of doing everything their teachers tell them (after all, if they werenÕt good at that they would have no chance of getting admitted to your university), so will mindlessly do whatever you assign no matter how worthless it is for them.
2. Care more about how your students will be different for having taken your class &lt;strong&gt;five years from now&lt;/strong&gt;, than what they can do while sitting on an uncomfortable chair for three hours on one particular day in December or what boxes they will check on some administratorÕs course evaluation form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much everything else follows from those two rules, but to save some time figuring out the technical aspects here are four simple things I have found most useful:
- DonÕt be afraid to bring the world into your classroom [danny lewin lecture, android 1B, etc.] or to bring your classroom to the world [cav daily, cs3102 videos, etc.]
- If you use projected slides (which sometimes is a good thing to do, but often not), invest $30 in a remote presenter so you can walk around the classroom and advance the slides and blank the screen without needing to find and fumble with your laptop.  If you are projecting slides, at least do it from a device where you can scribble on the slides dynamically so your presentation isnÕt completely static and canned.
- Yes, I said Òblank the screenÓ in the previous point.  It is one of the most effective and least used features of nearly all presentation software.  Nothing stops people from being transfixed into oblivion by looking at a projected image than having it suddenly disappear.
- When you ask your class a question, wait for what seems like an eternity to you before giving up on getting a student response.  What seems like an eternity to you when you are standing in front of a class, is probably barely enough time for the students to finish parsing your question, and certainly not enough for a slightly shy student to muster the courage to offer an answer.  Get someone to time how long Òwaiting for an eternityÓ actually is for you, and if it is less than 3 seconds figure out some trick to wait longer.  (I used to bring a capped water bottle for this, and would make sure to unscrew the cap, drink, and rescrew the cap, after asking a question.)
- DonÕt worry if you donÕt cover everything you planned to cover in class.  It is an awesome experience when you have a coherent lecture planned with a clear ending goal and it fits perfectly into the class time, but when things take longer than expected thatÕs usually a good sign that you have managed to engage students well!  Rather than trying to speed up to reach your target finish line on time, stop when the class is supposed to end.  If things go faster than you expected, donÕt feel the need to add filler as you get near the end of your prepared material.  Give the students a chance to ask questions about anything they want, and donÕt be afraid to end class early.  (I have yet to hear of a case where a student went to the administration to complain about not getting the full value they expect for the tuition they paid because their professor ended class before the agreed upon 75-minute length was completed.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-succeed-in-research:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How to Succeed in Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably the area in which other people are giving you the most advice, but the one where you least need it.  If you didnÕt already know how to do good research you wouldnÕt have been hired.&lt;br /&gt;
(ignominy of writing any journal papers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;administrate administrators
quote about football from time
In the military, people rise to the level of Generals by being
    telling parents of the 19-year olds who died as a result of their bad promotion decisions why their daughters wonÕt be coming home from Iraq.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;do they share your values?
- some do - best evidence is making some effort to continue meaningful
teaching (John Guttag, Ed Ayers, Terry Sullivan)
- most don&amp;rsquo;t - even those who start with similar values to yours, are
quickly corrupted by their sniffs of the trappings of power&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;later in your career, you might find you have to spend more time administrating administrators because youÕve taken on some administrative task yourself.  This requires a certain level of insanity, of course, since it involves giving up some of your idyllic life as a professor to do things that require administrative meetings, working with people that you donÕt get to choose yourself, and dealing with the stress and petty politics of administration.  Nevertheless, they may be occasions where the required suffering and time sacrifice is worth it if you think there are opportunities to have a lot more impact on something you value highly as well as to have some new experiences.  When evaluating the cost-benefit of such opportunities, donÕt minimize the expected time and suffering they involve, but also keep in mind that a small and focused amount of administrative effort can have ongoing impact long after youÕve stopped doing anything for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-avoid-stress-like-the-plague:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How to Avoid Stress Like the Plague&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first (and last) step here is to realize stress is the plague and act accordingly.  The physical health consequences of each day you are stressed are probably comparable to smoking a pack of cigarettes that day.  [I needed heart surgery when I was 35, despite having never smoked and being in semi-decent physical shape (at least by the standards of typical professors).  Other than genetics, the only risk factors my doctors could identify that might explain my condition was ÒstressÓ.]  Beyond the physical health consequence, stress will also destroy your mental creativity and productivity since instead of thinking about the interesting problems you care about with a clear mind, your mind will be distracted by the external stressors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find ways to prevent yourself from getting stressed out about things that arenÕt that important (which is pretty much everything related to your job as a faculty member).  When you have opportunities to do things that you know will cause you a great deal of stress, weigh carefully if the benefits of doing them outweigh the stress it will cause you (and donÕt underestimate how much that will be).   Its only worth taking on a stressful task like [organizing a major conference], [launching a new academic program], or [teaching a large class] if you think the long-term benefits of doing it will be really substantial (that is, substantial enough to reduce your overall stress level over the many following years) or the stress it would cause you to decline such an opportunity is more than the stress youÕll suffer by accepting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;stress about class lectures vs. visiting talks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-and-why-to-be-open:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How and Why to be Open&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-write-letters:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How to Write Letters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important opportunities you will have to advocate for
your students (as well as for faculty) is to write letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t think about this enough until recently, but here&amp;rsquo;s the advice I
wish I had followed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only agree to write a &lt;em&gt;recommendation&lt;/em&gt; letter in situations where you
genuinely would recommend the subject for the opporunity in question.
It is easy to say &amp;ldquo;sure&amp;rdquo; when asked to write someone a recommendation,
but painful to actually write letters for people you don&amp;rsquo;t think
highly of, or at least know well enough to have formed a strong
opinion.  For your own research students, of course, you should only
continue to advise them so long as you think highly of them and you
should be working with them closely enough to know them well.  But,
you will often be asked to write letters for other students&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later in your career, you may get asked to write letters to support
tenure cases of faculty.  This is a much trickier situation since the
person asking is not usually the candidate, but is the nominator of
the tenure case (usually the candidate&amp;rsquo;s department chair or dean).
The way this works at many institutions is the nominator can request
some fixed number &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; of letters, and must include all of the
responses in the cases.  In such cases, merely declining to write a
letter can be perceived as a bleak mark for the candidate (perhaps,
even worse than a mild letter would be), so you should be careful to
understand the implications on the candidate if you&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-adminstrate-administrators:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How to Adminstrate Administrators&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, academic institutions hire administrators based on their
successful track record as an administrator who come from other
backgrounds so they actually have administrative experiences and are not
immediately suspect for being willing to give up an idyllic as you might
expect, though, this kind of rationality is exceedingly rare for an
academy that hires its teachers based on how many ÒcountableÓ papers
they are able to publish while grad students.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-and-why-to-be-different:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How (and Why) to Be Different&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.nationalpost.com/2013/09/12/janice-lokelani-keihanaikukauakahihuliheekahaunaele/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+NP_Top_Stories+%28National+Post+-+Top+Stories%29&#34;&gt;http://news.nationalpost.com/2013/09/12/janice-lokelani-keihanaikukauakahihuliheekahaunaele/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+NP_Top_Stories+%28National+Post+-+Top+Stories%29&lt;/a&gt; -may make your life harder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-and-why-to-take-vacations:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How (and Why) to Take Vacations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[see RandyÕs advice!]
The main reason most professors (and other ambitious people) donÕt take enough vacations is because of the excessive fair that while they are vacationing, their rivals will be working hard so by vacationing they are putting the career at a disadvantage and if they are choosing problems to work on foolishly, perhaps even putting themselves in danger of being scooped.&lt;br /&gt;
The solution to this is to make everyone take vacations.  The Puritans accomplished this by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reformedreader.org/puritans/sabbath.puritan.newengland/sabbath.puritan.newengland.chapter17.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.reformedreader.org/puritans/sabbath.puritan.newengland/sabbath.puritan.newengland.chapter17.htm&lt;/a&gt;
more national holidays including
Qualification Day,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Programmer%27s_day&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Programmer%27s_day&lt;/a&gt; (which is officially recognized in Russia!)
Talk Like a Pirate Day &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.talklikeapirate.com/piratehome.html&#34;&gt;http://www.talklikeapirate.com/piratehome.html&lt;/a&gt;
Nikola Tesla Day (July 10),
Grace Hopper Day
Randy Pausch [sp?] Day
Malala Day (November 10),
Danny Lewin Day
and Alan Turing Day.  Romanian name days + publicly knowable + tradition of subject organizing and paying rather than a complex social burden for the friends and colleagues of the subject to negotiate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-be-a-head-and-not-a-chair:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How to be a Head (and not a Chair)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate to have John Guttag as my graduate advisor.  I also took
long enough to finish my degree, that while I was his student, he was
promoted from being a regular Professor, to an Assistant Department
Head, and then Department Head for MIT&amp;rsquo;s EECS.  Whenever anyone made the
mistake of calling him the &amp;ldquo;Chair&amp;rdquo; of the department, he was very quick
to object and point out the key difference: a department Chair is
appointed by the Dean, wheras a department Head is elected by the
faculty of the department.  Unfortunately, very few departments select
their administrators this way, but regardless of how one ends up in such
a position it is good to think of it as being a ÒHeadÓ and not a
ÒChairÓ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This distinction has a big impact in how administrators behave, and
applies more generally: a Chair is something that supports the asses
that rely on it to keep them from falling on the floor, where a Head is
something that provides leadership and direction for a large organism.
Whatever role you have and whether you got it through selection from
above or below, think of yourself as a Head and not a Chair.  Instead of
being the Chair of your research group who is burdened by the
administrative decisions and reports you need to make about your
underlings, be the Head of your research group who your students have
selected to lead, advise, and advocate for them.  Instead of being the
ÒInstructorÓ (Chair) of your class whose primarily role is to evaluate
your underlings to make it easier for the Dean to decide whom to put on
his list, be the Head of your class whose primary role is to facilitate
a good learning experience and environment for the students who have had
the temerity to select you as the person they want to take a class from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-and-when-to-manage:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;How (and When) to Manage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;advising styles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;nanomanage
   - grad school is not for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;micromanage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;millimanage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;manage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;unmanage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-to-leave-paradise:d5325ed100eb32a7122cabfecf637e33&#34;&gt;When to Leave Paradise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that&amp;rsquo;s not enough to blow the mind
of the typical person working, if you ever get bored or complacent,
every seven years or so you can go do something else, safe in the
knowledge that you can resume your university position after (oh, and
try explaining to the Wal-Mart employee that your university will
continue to pay half of your salary while you are off doing whatever you
want somewhere else).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reading and writing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spinach story:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sss.sagepub.com/content/44/4/638.full.pdf&#34;&gt;http://sss.sagepub.com/content/44/4/638.full.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feynman:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://genius.cat-v.org/richard-feynman/writtings/letters/problems&#34;&gt;http://genius.cat-v.org/richard-feynman/writtings/letters/problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;huge amount of time -&amp;gt; ordinary result
huge amount of time + epsilon -&amp;gt; extraordinary result For many
activities, epsilon is actually just a quite small constant - that&amp;rsquo;s why
the results are called &lt;em&gt;extraordinary&lt;/em&gt; not &lt;em&gt;EXPordinary&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/1987/10/23/obituaries/an-kolmogorov-dies-at-84-top-russian-mathematician.html&#34;&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/1987/10/23/obituaries/an-kolmogorov-dies-at-84-top-russian-mathematician.html&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; Dr. Kolmogorov and his students, who included the top Soviet
mathematicians, were responsible for keeping their country at the
forefront of mathematics internationally in an era when other areas of
Soviet science lagged. His students considered him an unusual guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He never explained anything, just posed problems,&amp;rdquo; one of them,
V. I. Arnold, once said. &amp;ldquo;He didn&amp;rsquo;t chew them over. He gave the student
complete independence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Paradise!</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/welcome/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;paradise&#34;&gt;
&lt;img id=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;./images/paradise-edited.png&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; alt=&#34;Paradise!&#34;&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;overlaytext&#34;&gt;Welcome to Paradise!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul Graham &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paulgraham.com/college.html&#34;&gt;once wrote&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Almost everyone hates their dissertation by the time they&amp;rsquo;re done with it. The process inherently
  tends to produce an unpleasant result, like a cake made out of whole
  wheat flour and baked for twelve hours. Few dissertations are read
  with pleasure, especially by their authors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And aside from that, grad school is &lt;strong&gt;close to paradise&lt;/strong&gt;. Many people
  remember it as the happiest time of their lives. And nearly all the
  rest, including me, remember it as a period that would have been, if
  they hadn&amp;rsquo;t had to write a dissertation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a professor reading this now, you&amp;rsquo;ve most likely finished your
dissertation already and know enough algebra to reach the obvious
conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./images/algebra-small.png&#34; align=center&#34;
alt=&#34;gradstuent+dissertation=paradise&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; border=0&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the apparent correctness of my algebra, I encounter many young
professors who are stressed and unhappy, and many older ones who are
miserable and bitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How can this be&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a
href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/u/0/photos/114975801512009922265/albums/5692219070649609345&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./images/IMG_2712.jpg&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;professor-s-paradisical-paradox:2cc7dc244eed4480e8b46c91e911e96b&#34;&gt;Professor&amp;rsquo;s Paradisical Paradox&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traditional view of paradise is sitting on a quiet Carribbean beach
while scantily clad attractive young people of your preferred gender
bring a steady stream of fancy drinks with umbrellas in them, with
nothing to do but watch the waves on the beach and permanent sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be good for a few days a year, but as a permanent life sounds
quite horrifying!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;True paradise is being able to do things you find personally,
intellectually, and socially gratifying.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No job provides a better freedom and opportunity to do this than being a
professor.  So, &lt;em&gt;if being a professor is making you miserable, you must
be doing something wrong!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/u/0/photos/114975801512009922265/albums/5692195893088532193/5692197259652743330?pid=5692197259652743330&amp;oid=114975801512009922265&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./images/realwork.jpg&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34; alt=&#34;What Real Work Looks Like&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;rightcaption&#34; style=&#34;margin-top:402px&#34;&gt;Try Explaining to Her&lt;br&gt;Why You Should Get a Sabbatical&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
If you&amp;rsquo;re not convinced that you are in paradise yet, consider how
idyllic and unimaginable your job would seem to anyone who has a &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;
job: you get paid a generous salary for having the freedom to work on
anything you want, whenever you want, and however you want, with no boss
to report to, no time cards to punch, and (essentially&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2cc7dc244eed4480e8b46c91e911e96b:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2cc7dc244eed4480e8b46c91e911e96b:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) no risk of
getting fired no matter what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, you get to work with smart and interesting people, and can
choose whomever you want to work with from both your own institution and
its &amp;ldquo;competitors&amp;rdquo;.  You get the opportunity to teach, interact with, and
potentially inspire generations of creative and ambitious students.  You
lack any serious responsibilities or burdens of command, and don&amp;rsquo;t have
to make any life-or-death decisions.  You can fail without serious
consequences, and its fine if you change your mind about what you want
to do.  And, if you get bored, you can go do something else for a year
or more (and even keep getting part of your salary!), safe in the
knowledge that you can return to your cushy academic position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sounds like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://yourstory.in/2013/10/david-evans-udacity/&#34;&gt;best job in the world to
me&lt;/a&gt;, and I hope it
does to you too!  If you don&amp;rsquo;t see this as an imaginably privileged and
marvelous existence you should quit now and open up a position for
someone who is likely to make better use of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;./advice&#34; class=&#34;button_accent&#34;&gt;Next:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;How
to Ignore Advice&amp;nbsp;&amp;rarr;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2cc7dc244eed4480e8b46c91e911e96b:1&#34;&gt;I know of a dean at an unnamed prestigious university claimed that the difference between a professor without tenure and one with tenure is that firing the one without tenure takes one phone call, but he needs two calls to fire the one with tenure.  The reality is, though, as long as a tenured professor doesn&amp;rsquo;t do something to upset a major donor or put the institution at legal risk, they are exceedingly unlikely to be fired.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2cc7dc244eed4480e8b46c91e911e96b:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Ignore Advice</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/advice/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;photohead&#34;&gt;
&lt;img id=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;../images/psychic-3.jpg&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; alt=&#34;Ignoring Advice&#34;&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;overlaytext&#34; style=&#34;text-align:left;padding-top:0px;top:-40px;left:0px;right:200px;color:#EEFFCC&#34;&gt;How to Ignore Advice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a new faculty member, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably have scores of people wanting
to give you advice, not to mention documents like this one.  Getting
advice is easy, and giving advice is even easier than that, but figuring
out which advice to ignore is much harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;rightnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;a style=&#34;border-bottom:none;&#34; href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20150804111049/http://blogs.scientificamerican.com/guest-blog/the-awesomest-7-year-postdoc-or-how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-love-the-tenure-track-faculty-life/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/rad-monkeys-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;220&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Every new faculty member should read Radhika Nagpal&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20150804111049/http://blogs.scientificamerican.com/guest-blog/the-awesomest-7-year-postdoc-or-how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-love-the-tenure-track-faculty-life/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Awesomest
7-Year Postdoc or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the
Tenure-Track Faculty
Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Her
first main realization is &lt;b&gt;&amp;ldquo;I stopped taking advice&amp;rdquo;&lt;/b&gt;, which is advice you should
definitely follow!
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;types-of-advice:7e88da48c1ab1067dbe244fe61fdff60&#34;&gt;Types of Advice&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two main types of advice: &lt;strong&gt;consensus&lt;/strong&gt; advice, which comes from
committees or similar well-vetted sources; and &lt;strong&gt;individual&lt;/strong&gt; advice,
which is the mostly unfiltered view of a single person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consensus advice is usually &lt;em&gt;correct&lt;/em&gt; (since lots of people agreed on
it), generally &lt;em&gt;agreeable&lt;/em&gt; (no one on the committee objected to it), and
nearly always &lt;em&gt;uninteresting&lt;/em&gt; (anything everyone agrees with is unlikely
to be nonobvious or surprising).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individual advice is nearly always &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; (its just one arrogant
person&amp;rsquo;s opinion), usually &lt;em&gt;disagreeable&lt;/em&gt; (it is based only on their
personal circumstances and experience, and yours are certainly
different), but often &lt;em&gt;interesting&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; (since some indvidual
felt strongly about it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, see if you can guess which of the recommendations below
came from a &amp;ldquo;committee&amp;rdquo; and which from an &amp;ldquo;individual&amp;rdquo;:
&lt;table width=&#34;100%&#34; cellpadding=10&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34; width=&#34;64%&#34; bgcolor=&#34;#FFFFAA&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The truth is that no ideal strategy has yet been found, and that every
approach has strengths and weaknesses. Given the current state of the
art in this area, we are convinced that no one-size-fits-all approach
will succeed at all institutions. Because introductory programs differ
so dramatically in their goals, structure, resources, and intended
audience, we need a range of strategies that have been validated by
practice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onclick=&#34;showText(&#39;text1&#39;,&#39;text2&#39;)&#34; href=&#34;javascript:void(0);&#34;&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;text2&#34; class=&#34;show&#34;&gt;[Reveal source]&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;div id=&#34;text1&#34; class=&#34;hide&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.acm.org/education/education/education/curric_vols/cc2001.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ACM Computing Curricula 2001: Recommendations of the Joint ACM/IEEE Task Force on Computing Curricula&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  A &amp;ldquo;Joint Committee&amp;rdquo; is even less likely to produce something useful than a normal committee!  The quoted section is proceeded by &amp;ldquo;In the interest of promoting peace among the warring factions, the CC2001 Task Force has chosen not to recommend any single approach. &amp;ldquo;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34; bgcolor=&#34;#AAFFFF&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The use of COBOL cripples the mind; its teaching should, therefore, be
regarded as a criminal offense. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onclick=&#34;showText(&#39;ewd1&#39;,&#39;prompt&#39;)&#34; href=&#34;javascript:void(0);&#34;&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;prompt&#34; class=&#34;show&#34;&gt;[Reveal source]&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;div id=&#34;ewd1&#34; class=&#34;hide&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../images/ewd-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;
Edsger W. Dijkstra, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs655/readings/ewd498.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do we tell truths that might hurt?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 1975.  Note
that Java didn’t exist yet when Dijksra wrote this, so &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/114975801512009922265/posts/7QRogdYbBQ3&#34;&gt;Grace Hopper fans&lt;/a&gt; may be able to forgive him for picking unfairly on COBOL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My meta-advice is that unless you feel particularly unprepared you
shouldn&amp;rsquo;t waste much time on &amp;ldquo;committee&amp;rdquo; advice.  Everyone should,
however, &lt;strong&gt;read and listen to lots of advice from individuals&lt;/strong&gt;, but
&lt;strong&gt;ignore most of it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two things you should think about in taking any advice are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How it applies to you &amp;mdash; the person giving it has probably had very
different life experiences from you, and may even have different values
and goals.  You should be careful to weigh any advice you receive in
light of these differences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether the person giving it has any incentives that don&amp;rsquo;t align with
your own.  This mostly applies to advice you may receive from
administrators, whose goals or values may not be well-aligned with yours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/evans/paradise/others/&#34;&gt;Other Advice&lt;/a&gt; for links to some advice from
othe individuals that I think is particularly worth reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-you-shouldn-t-listen-to-me:7e88da48c1ab1067dbe244fe61fdff60&#34;&gt;Why You Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Listen to Me&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some reasons you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t follow most of my advice
here:&lt;img src=&#34;../images/lucky.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; height=&#34;253&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34; alt=&#34;lucky&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;strong&gt;extremely lucky&lt;/strong&gt;.  Many of the things that have worked
out well for me could easily have been dismal failures if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been
so fortunate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started my professorial career back in 1999, when most things were
much easier than they are today.  I hope things haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten much
worse for new faculty, but I fear that some major things have (at least
in computer security research and most other computing research areas,
things have certainly gotten more crowded).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had the good fortune to spend my career in a growing field at a
wonderful university in a town that has been &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/jul/27/happiness-place-called-charlottesville-virginia&#34;&gt;scientifically proven to be the
happiest in all of the US&lt;/a&gt;, recognized as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedailymeal.com/america-s-best-small-towns-food-2013-slideshow&#34;&gt;America&amp;rsquo;s best small town for food&lt;/a&gt;, and as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://usatoday30.usatoday.com/life/lifestyle/2004-03-29-best-cities-main_x.htm&#34;&gt;best place to live in the US&lt;/a&gt;.  That said, the experience of most faculty
at research-focused universities in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j9XZSgDAtSQ&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;endless golden-age
fields&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has a fair bit in
common, so I think most of my experience is not that different from what
I&amp;rsquo;ve heard others have experienced in similar fields.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dori-mic.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/dm-side-2.jpg&#34;
width=&#34;250&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34; alt=&#34;Dori-Mic and the Universal
Machine&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I had no major personal responsibilities until long
after tenure (this was not by planning, but just the way things worked
out for me).  I hope those of you who have children earlier will still
be able to have a paradasical professorship, but I guess some things may
be a lot easier for me to say than they would be to do for people in
that scenario.  (I do have one small offering to help new professors
with young children.  One of the most stressful things I&amp;rsquo;m sure you are
worrying about is how embarrassing it will be to you if your child ends
up behind other students in her kindergraten class in theoretical
computer science. Luckily, there is now &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dori-mic.org&#34;&gt;a book to help with this&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-you-might-listen:7e88da48c1ab1067dbe244fe61fdff60&#34;&gt;Why You Might Listen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I do hope you are still willing to read on and perhaps listen
to some of my advice.  So, here are reasons why you might:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.virginia.edu/content/master-teachers-called-spread-their-expertise-grounds&#34;&gt;master
teacher&lt;/a&gt;,
but I have taught over a half million students and learned a fair bit from many of them and a great deal from a handful of them.     &lt;div id=&#34;imageblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;A align=&#34;left&#34; id=&#34;noline&#34; href=&#34;http://www.rust-class.org/0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;../images/rustclass-4.jpg&#34; width=320 height=180&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a align=&#34;right&#34; id=&#34;noline&#34; href=&#34;http://blog.udacity.com/2013/02/cs101-one-year-later.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;../images/udacityparty-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a align=&#34;left&#34; id=&#34;noline&#34; href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/cs1120-f11/&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;../images/cs1120-2.jpg&#34; width=320&#34;&gt;&lt;a align=&#34;right&#34; id=&#34;noline&#34; href=&#34;http://www.jeffersonswheel.org/2011/hoos-at-usenix&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;../images/hoos-with-me-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a research superstar, but my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/pubs/usenix08/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;starbug number&amp;rdquo; is 1&lt;/a&gt; and I did manage to make full professor at a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/09/16/magazine/teresa-sullivan-uva-ouster.html?hpw&#34;&gt;s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/brains-but-not-bucks-u-va-says-tough-luck/2013/08/09/7651fcc2-0070-11e3-9a3e-916de805f65d_story.html&#34;&gt;e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2013/sep/9/college-athletic-departments-in-virginia-get-an-av/&#34;&gt;m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.collegiatetimes.com/databases/salaries/university-of-virginia-2010&#34;&gt;i&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.baconsrebellion.com/2012/06/what-disruptive-change-looks-like.html&#34;&gt;-&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.virginia.edu/uvatours/shorthistory/&#34;&gt;r&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nps.gov/nr/twhp/wwwlps/lessons/92uva/92uva.htm&#34;&gt;e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.monticello.org/site/jefferson/quotations-university-virginia&#34;&gt;s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Backus&#34;&gt;p&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://artsandsciences.virginia.edu/woodson/works/gaston-honor.html&#34;&gt;e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com&#34;&gt;c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ohours.org&#34;&gt;t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hipmunk.com&#34;&gt;a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tina_Fey&#34;&gt;b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boyd_Tinsley&#34;&gt;l&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walter_Reed&#34;&gt;e&lt;/a&gt; institution without the ignominy of writing a single journal paper.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also managed to produce &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/students/&#34;&gt;some remarkable students&lt;/a&gt;, win &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.virginia.edu/content/uva-computer-scientist-david-evans-wins-statewide-outstanding-faculty-award&#34;&gt;some awards&lt;/a&gt;, and according to Prospect Magazine to be
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20121008104922/http://www.prospectmagazine.co.uk/magazine/online-universities-udacity-grand-challenge-david-stavens-dave-evans/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;the kind of nerdy savant whose gap-tooth smile and Monty Python humour attract a cult following on campus&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;img src=&#34;../images/promotion.png&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=600&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;rightnote&#34;&gt;
Actual page from my full promotion dossier (third attempt, which was successful).
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../images/tj.jpg&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; alt=&#34;Thomas Jefferson&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;rightcaption&#34; style=&#34;margin-top:265px;opacity:0.8&#34;&gt;
I never met Mr. Jefferson&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amacad.org/multimedia/pdfs/publications/bookofmembers/ChapterJ.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:70%; position:relative; bottom: 0.5em;&#34;&gt;AAAS&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but he is an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.monticello.org/site/jefferson/quotations-idleness&#34;&gt;outstanding virtual mentor&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to learn closely from some truly exceptional
and amazing people including but not limited to (in roughly chronological order) my mother&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;father&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nae.edu/MembersSection/Directory20412/29413.aspx&#34;&gt;NAE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;,
Marc&amp;nbsp;Raibert&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nae.edu/MembersSection/Directory20412/28022.aspx&#34;&gt;NAE&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/12/14/technology/google-adds-to-its-menagerie-of-robots.html&#34;&gt;GBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;,
John&amp;nbsp;Backus&lt;sup&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amacad.org/multimedia/pdfs/publications/bookofmembers/ChapterB.pdf&#34;&gt;AAAS&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amturing.acm.org/award_winners/backus_0703524.cfm&#34;&gt;AMT&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nae.edu/MembersSection/Directory20412/29745.aspx&#34;&gt;NAE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;,
Barbara&amp;nbsp;Liskov&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amacad.org/multimedia/pdfs/publications/bookofmembers/ChapterL.pdf&#34;&gt;AAAS&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amturing.acm.org/award_winners/liskov_1108679.cfm&#34;&gt;AMT&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nae.edu/MembersSection/Directory20412/27743.aspx&#34;&gt;NAE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;,
John&amp;nbsp;Guttag&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amacad.org/multimedia/pdfs/publications/bookofmembers/ChapterG.pdf&#34;&gt;AAAS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;,
Anita&amp;nbsp;Jones&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amacad.org/multimedia/pdfs/publications/bookofmembers/ChapterJ.pdf&#34;&gt;AAAS&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nae.edu/MembersSection/Directory20412/27636.aspx&#34;&gt;NAE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;,
Mary&amp;nbsp;Lou&amp;nbsp;Soffa&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sighpc.org/recognition/kennedy-award&#34;&gt;KKA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;,
Sebastian&amp;nbsp;Thrun&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nae.edu/MembersSection/Directory20412/30800.aspx&#34;&gt;NAE&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;GBC&lt;/sup&gt;, and Peter&amp;nbsp;Norvig&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amacad.org/multimedia/pdfs/publications/bookofmembers/ChapterN.pdf&#34;&gt;AAAS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (not to mention many students, former students, and colleagues).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, the two most important reasons I hope you will listen to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am extraordinarily happy and extremely fulfilled with my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I believe in everything I&amp;rsquo;ve written here strongly enough, that if you
read it and are not convinced, I&amp;rsquo;m willing to buy you coffee (even the
super venti salted caramel mocha from Starbucks if you are into that
sort of thing) to discuss it further.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../time&#34; class=&#34;button_accent&#34;&gt;Next:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;How to Spend Your Time&amp;nbsp;&amp;rarr;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Spend Your Time</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/time/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;photohead&#34;&gt;
&lt;img id=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;../images/time.jpg&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; alt=&#34;time&#34;&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;overlaytext&#34; style=&#34;right:20px;left:370px;top:100px;color:#eeff66;text-align:right;font-size:38px&#34;&gt;How to Spend Your Time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important decisions you make are how to use your time.  Use your time in a way that &lt;strong&gt;reflects your values.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deciding what you value is a difficult and important question, and I
can&amp;rsquo;t presume to tell you what the answer should be for you.  I do
believe, though, that everyone who becomes a professor in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j9XZSgDAtSQ&#34;&gt;endless
golden-age field&lt;/a&gt; shares at
least these three core values:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People matter.&lt;/strong&gt;  It is rewarding and gratifying to do things that
have a positive impact on other people, and painful to do things that
are harmful to other people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowlege matters.&lt;/strong&gt; The future should be better than the present,
just like the present is better than the past.  The vast majority of
human lives have been massively improved by scientific and technological
progress.  Contributing to and sharing that progress is a worthy and
noble endeavour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freedom matters.&lt;/strong&gt; Being able to do, say, and think what you want
is valuable and important, as is empowering and enabling others to be
free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you figure out what you value, you should aim to spend your time in
ways that are consistent with those values, both in the short-term and
long-term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-snub-work-life-balance:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a&#34;&gt;How to Snub &amp;ldquo;Work-Life Balance&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll hear advice from many people on how to achieve &lt;em&gt;Work-Life
Balance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but &amp;ldquo;Work-Life&amp;rdquo; balance is a ridiculous goal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/worklife.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t aim to &lt;em&gt;balance&lt;/em&gt; work and life.  Your life is everything.
The only thing that matters is your personal mental and physical health
and that of your family and close friends.  You should aim to make your
work a fulfilling and meaningful part of your life, not something to
balance against it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;rightnote&#34;&gt;
   &lt;em&gt;Kids are great. You guys should all have kids! I don&amp;rsquo;t see mine enough actually. What I find is I&amp;rsquo;m able to be with them and still be on e-mail. I can be with them and still be working at the same time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vanityfair.com/online/daily/2013/03/elon-musk-die-mars&#34;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people have to make difficult life-work decisions: generals,
presidents, and certain
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/early-lead/wp/2013/09/16/joe-flacco-misses-birth-of-son-to-play-for-ravens/&#34;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/11/10/sports/football/nfl-coaches-in-charge-and-at-risk.html&#34;&gt;think&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.buzzfeed.com/andrewkaczynski/the-time-terry-mccauliffe-left-the-delivery-for-a-washington&#34;&gt;their
jobs&lt;/a&gt;
are so important they need to also.  If you think that extra hour a week
you could spend working on your research instead of with your family
will enable you prove &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; != &lt;em&gt;NP&lt;/em&gt; it may be justifiably hard to decide
whether it is worth the risk that you&amp;rsquo;ll miss &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dorina.org/pubs/kleene.html&#34;&gt;your daughter&amp;rsquo;s first
encounter with a base case&lt;/a&gt;, but
fortunately I&amp;rsquo;m not smart enough to have to worry about that (and
probably you aren&amp;rsquo;t either).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;rightnote&#34;&gt;
   &lt;em&gt;The couples with which Sandberg is familiar seem to be ones in which nannies and cleaners do most of the household and child-related work. &amp;hellip; The authors cite a couple in Massachusetts that I actually know. The mom is a bigshot at a non-profit organization. The dad is a child psychiatrist who, according to Sandberg, “leaned in” to do far more than the traditional male share of child rearing. Perhaps he did, but this couple has twins that are about the same age as Greta, my 3.5-year-old, so I see the kids a lot. Of the 50 or so times that I’ve seen the twins, were they with mom or dad? Once they were with mom. Once they were with both parents. 48 times they were with a Brazilian nanny.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/philg/2013/03/26/lean-in-women-can-move-up-the-career-ladder-as-soon-as-men-change/&#34;&gt;Philip Greenspun&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conclusion to draw from this, though, is not that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t
&lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; at all, but that you should do &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; only insofar as it
contributes to your &lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt;.  For most people, this should mean doing
work that is beneficial for your personal fulfillment and self-respect
as well as for making your family proud to be related to you, and to
hopefully be the role model you want for your children.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-much-should-you-work:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a&#34;&gt;How Much Should You Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To most of humanity, &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; is the stuff you do solely because if you
didn&amp;rsquo;t your employer might fire you.  By this definition, as a professor
you should aim to work no more than 10 hours a year, and ideally reduce
that number to zero if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the main work I do each year is filling out the asinine annual
report forms our school requires.  There are two separate forms to
submit for this.  The first is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/docs/seas-annual.docx&#34;&gt;painfully long Word
document&lt;/a&gt; that
requires fitting lots of text into strangely formatted boxes to answer
awkwardly-posed questions that reflect poorly on the Dean&amp;rsquo;s values and
competence (e.g., &amp;ldquo;List courses in which you incorporated new teaching
techniques (e.g., inclusion of computing, use of multimedia equipment,
etc.)&amp;ldquo;) as well as a final page meant to quantify one&amp;rsquo;s value by
counting things like &amp;ldquo;Copyrighted software&amp;rdquo;.
   &lt;div class=&#34;rightnote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of work.  Make work afraid of you. I did such a fabulous job of making work afraid of me that it has avoided me my whole life so far.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cartalk.com/blogs/staff-blog/tom-magliozzi-1937-2014&#34;&gt;Tom Magliozzi&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is a one-page form where you have to self-rate yourself
according to a rubric that has been plainstakingly devised by an endless
series of committees.  As an example, here&amp;rsquo;s the teaching rubric:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/seas-rubric.jpg&#34; width=640&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the teaching rubric doesn&amp;rsquo;t include even a single item that
has anything to do with the faculty member is actually doing anything
that contributes to &lt;em&gt;students actually learning&lt;/em&gt;, but the only thing one
needs to do to move up from &amp;ldquo;Does Not Meet Expectations&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Partially
Meets Expectations&amp;rdquo; is to cancel classes!  Happily, this is enough to be
satisfactory as far as the school is concerned, so as long as faculty
notice the rubric with at least two classes left in the semester in time
to cancel them, there is no risk of obtaining an unsatisfactory teaching
rating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filling out these forms takes about 4-10 hours of soul-crushing work to
complete.  More principled faculty than me refuse to fill these in, but
since faculty who fail to submit them are not considered for raises, it
seems worth it to me to cynically spend the time it requires each year
to do this.  The suffering it involves is at least somewhat balanced by
the realization that I have to do this for a few hours each year, but
many people have jobs where their entire job is doing similarly
soul-crushing work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from filling in the annual report for the school, the other main
work I do each year is financial administration and reporting for my
research grants.  I avoid as much as possible grants with high
administrative requirements (such as those from DARPA or IARPA), so this
typically requires only a few hours per year (about an hour per $100,000
spent, which seems pretty reasonable, and the financial administration
staff in our department does a great job of taking care of most of the
hard parts).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-spend-the-rest-of-your-time:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a&#34;&gt;How to Spend the Rest of Your Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than the 10-20 hours per year that you have to work, for the rest
of your time you have essentially complete freedom how you spend it.
That freedom comes with some obligation to spend your time in ways that
benefit humanity, but very few other constraints or obligations.  This
is one of the best things about being a professor, but is something very
few faculty seem to take much advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/mattercount.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; height=&#34;193&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34; alt=&#34;matter vs. count&#34;&gt;
Tenure-track faculty often complicate things by thinking there is a
dilemma between spending time on &amp;ldquo;things that matter&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;things that
&lt;em&gt;count&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; for getting tenure.  Contrary to what many new faculty believe,
there is no secret list of &amp;ldquo;countable&amp;rdquo; things that is hidden in a deep
corner of Tenureville (at least, if there is, I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet reach a
sufficient depth to gain access to it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting tenure is just about convincing 12-25 people who have it that
you deserve it.  Fortunately, most of those people should have values
that are well-aligned with yours, so if you focus on doing things that
matter well that should be enough for them.  The others are either
people who feel like they endured a certain amount of suffering doing
silly things to get tenure so want to make sure everyone else does (in
other domains this is called &lt;em&gt;hazing&lt;/em&gt;), or administrators whose values
may have been corrupted by many years away from paradise.  You should
hope that such people will be convinced by the others, or at least,
won&amp;rsquo;t have power over them.  But, rest assured that even if you don&amp;rsquo;t
get tenure, if you&amp;rsquo;ve focused on things that matter you will have plenty
of good options of other things to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-be-mediocre-not:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a&#34;&gt;How to Be Mediocre (Not!)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It natural to think there is a linear relationship to the amount of
energy expended on something and the quality or value of the result, but
the reality is much different.  For most things professors do, it looks
something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/mediocrity.png&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;310&#34;&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes a farily minimal amount of effort to cross the &lt;em&gt;threshold of
non-embarrassment&lt;/em&gt;, but effort beyond that if unlikely to create much
added value, until really significant energy is put into something to
reach the level of &lt;em&gt;observably extraordinarinary&lt;/em&gt;.  For many tasks, its not
even clear if extra effort improves value for most of the middle range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to manage your time most effectively without risking embarrassment,
you should do enough to just cross the threshold of non-embarrassment
for all but the tasks you are most passionate about, and reserve all the
energy you can to devote to those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, you would avoid taking on any tasks that you don&amp;rsquo;t feel
strongly enough about to want to reach the pinnacle of
extraordinariness.  But, you may take on more than you end up having
time for and have to triage.  In such cases, much better to identify one
thing to reach for extraordinariness on and just aim to cross the
non-embarrassment threshold on everything else, rather than to end up
doing everything in a mediocre way.  It is also the case that even tasks
that you feel strongly about (e.g., teaching) are often composed of
several subtasks, many of which are neither exciting nor terribly
important (e.g., grading) but can be huge time-killers if you get
trapped striving to move through the trough of mediocrity.  Focus on the
subtasks you care most about and are uniquely able to contribute to, and
aim do the rest at just about the embarrassment level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-manage-time:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a&#34;&gt;How to Manage Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best advice I&amp;rsquo;ve seen on time management is Randy Pausch&amp;rsquo;s lecture
(see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~robins/Randy/&#34;&gt;Gabe Robins&amp;rsquo; site for more background on
Randy&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/oTugjssqOT0?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to add to Randy&amp;rsquo;s talk, which I would encourage
everyone to watch, but mention a few specific things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-to-avoid-telephone-interruptions:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a&#34;&gt;How to Avoid Telephone Interruptions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t have an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/phone/&#34;&gt;office telephone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a:3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-to-schedule-and-be-scheduled:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a&#34;&gt;How to Schedule and Be Scheduled&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most essential but hardest things to do is to rigorously
block off time for important things.  If you start with a blank
calendar, and fill it up with meetings, leaving the remaining time for
important stuff, there is a big risk that you end up with no time left
for anything important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should instead start by putting all the really important things on
your calendar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Family time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time to exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time for reading, thinking, and creating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time for fun/relaxing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block our real entries on your calendar with as much time as you need
for these, and treat them like &lt;strong&gt;real appointments&lt;/strong&gt;.  You might need to
reschedule them occasionally, but don&amp;rsquo;t just cancel them to make room
for inessential meetings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;rightnote&#34;&gt;
   &lt;em&gt;Be ruthless about protecting writing days, i.e., do not cave in to
endless requests to have &amp;ldquo;essential&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;long overdue&amp;rdquo; meetings on
those days. The funny thing is that, although writing has been my actual
job for several years now, I still seem to have to fight for time in
which to do it. Some people do not seem to grasp that I still have to
sit down in peace and write the books, apparently believing that they
pop up like mushrooms without my connivance. I must therefore &lt;strong&gt;guard the
time allotted to writing as a Hungarian Horntail guards its firstborn
egg.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/quotes/163742-be-ruthless-about-protecting-writing-days-i-e-do-not-cave&#34;&gt;J.K. Rowling&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, schedule your classes, meetings with students, research meetings,
and with anytime leftover, any other meetings you think are more
worthwhile than having extra time for family or thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve found it useful to ask all of my research students to respond to a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://whenisgood.net&#34;&gt;whenisgood.net&lt;/a&gt; request to provide me their
regular schedule, and use this to schedule both regular and irregular
meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-and-why-to-take-vacations:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a&#34;&gt;How (and Why) to Take Vacations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;rightbar&#34; src=&#34;../images/ready.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; alt=&#34;ready&#34;&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;rightcaption&#34; style=&#34;margin-top:5px;&#34;&gt;Getting Ready for a Productive Research Day&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; jobs, as a professor you can effectively take as much
vacation as you want, whenever you want (except when you have classes to
teach).  Despite this, most professors seem to never or rarely take
vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you suffer from this, the way to get over it is to realize that your
main goal as a researcher is to come up with &lt;strong&gt;one or two good ideas a
year&lt;/strong&gt;, and a &lt;strong&gt;great idea every decade&lt;/strong&gt;.  You are much more likely to come
up with those good-great ideas if you are relaxed, in a new environment,
and having time to daydream, sleep well, and have new experiences, than
if you are stressed out in your office trying to appear productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason most professors don’t take enough vacations is because
of the excessive fear they have that while they are vacationing, their
rivals will be working hard so by vacationing they are putting the
career at a disadvantage and if they are choosing problems to work on
foolishly, perhaps even putting themselves in danger of being scooped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution to this is to make everyone take vacations.  The Puritans
accomplished this by imposing fines and whippings on anyone caught
working on the sabbath, but such penalties are hard to enforce today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;rightnote&#34;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Profanation of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Day shall be punished by fine, imprisonment, or corporeal punishment; and if proudly, and with a high hand against the authority of God&amp;ndash;with death.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20140214214537/http://reformedreader.org/puritans/sabbath.puritan.newengland/sabbath.puritan.newengland.chapter17.htm&#34;&gt;New Haven code of laws, quoted in &lt;em&gt;The Sabbath in Puritan New England&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To allay any guilt you might have just taking vacations for their own
sake, I encourage you to observe important these universal holidays:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.law.duke.edu/cspd/publicdomainday&#34;&gt;Public&amp;nbsp;Domain&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;),
One-Two-Three Day&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;23&lt;/sub&gt;), Doubling Day&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;24&lt;/sub&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.piday.org/&#34;&gt;&amp;lfloor;&amp;pi;&amp;rfloor;
Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;14&lt;/sub&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.maxwellevans.net&#34;&gt;Post-Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;18&lt;/sub&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rust-class.org/0/class5.html&#34;&gt;Qualification&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(nationality-dependent),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coindesk.com/bitcoin-pizza-day-celebrating-pizza-bought-10000-btc/&#34;&gt;Bitcoin Pizza Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;22&lt;/sub&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://xkcd.com/1292/&#34;&gt;Pau&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/doodles/alan-turings-100th-birthday&#34;&gt;Alan&amp;nbsp;Turing&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;23&lt;/sub&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tauday.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;lfloor;&amp;tau;&amp;rfloor;&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;28&lt;/sub&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dorina.org/&#34;&gt;&amp;lceil;&amp;tau;&amp;rceil;&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;29&lt;/sub&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teslasociety.com/tesla_day.htm&#34;&gt;Nikola&amp;nbsp;Tesla&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wends&#34;&gt;Wends&amp;rsquo;&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(after&amp;nbsp;most&amp;nbsp;Tuesdays), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/09/tech/innovation/danny-lewin-9-11-akamai/&#34;&gt;Danny&amp;nbsp;Lewin&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cEBtO25xW-o&#34;&gt;Norman&amp;nbsp;Borlaug&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.talklikeapirate.com/piratehome.html&#34;&gt;Talk&amp;nbsp;Like&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;Pirate&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;19&lt;/sub&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Randy_Pausch&#34;&gt;Randy&amp;nbsp;Pausch&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;23&lt;/sub&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://radar.oreilly.com/2011/10/dennis-ritchie-day.html&#34;&gt;Dennis&amp;nbsp;Ritchie&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;30&lt;/sub&gt;),
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/doodles/grace-hoppers-107th-birthday&#34;&gt;Grace&amp;nbsp;Hopper&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;9&lt;/sub&gt;),
and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isaac_Newton&#34;&gt;Isaac&amp;nbsp;Netwon&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;25&lt;/sub&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../teaching/&#34; class=&#34;button_accent&#34;&gt;Next:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;How to Be an Extraordinary Teacher&amp;nbsp;&amp;rarr;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a:1&#34;&gt;This website is based on a talk I first gave at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity14/birds-feather-sessions#colloquium&#34;&gt;Doctoral Colloquim at USENIX Security Symposium 2014&lt;/a&gt; which was followed by a panel on &amp;ldquo;Work-Life Balance&amp;rdquo; (which ran until after 9pm on an evening during the conference).  Of the three panelists, two advocated for the &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t have a life&amp;rdquo; and questioned the premise of the panel.  The third, thankfully, was at least somewhat on the fence about having a life being a good thing, but early enough in her career to be unsure how compatible this was with being a professor.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a:2&#34;&gt;In some countries, it may also be necessary to work to generate enough income to provide for your family&amp;rsquo;s subsistence and basic needs. It is probably not necessary to work at all to do this, though, in &lt;a href=&#34;http://opinionator.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/11/02/poverty-in-america-is-mainstream/?src=me&amp;amp;ref=general&#34;&gt;semi-developed countries like the United States&lt;/a&gt; (and certainly not in fully-developed countries like Canada) that are rich and moral enough to provide basic nutrition, shelter and adequate health coverage to all their citizens.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a:3&#34;&gt;Actually getting rid of ones office phone is harder than you might think, at least at my university.  I tried for several years to officially have my phone removed and save the University from having to pay for it, but failed to make any headway on this, and eventually gave up and just put the phone in a file cabinet.  This worked for a few years, but a recent horrendously expensive university-wide effort to &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.virginia.edu/content/university-s-first-voip-phones-make-their-maiden-flight&#34;&gt;upgrade phones to use VoIP&lt;/a&gt;, led to me being asked several times what kind of new tethered phone I wanted in my office.  Despite stating I didn&amp;rsquo;t want one, someone snuck one into my office last week, and now the department is paying several hundred dollars a year for me to keep it in my file cabinet.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a:3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Be an Extraordinary Teacher</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/teaching/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;photohead&#34;&gt;
&lt;img id=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;../images/cow.jpg&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; alt=&#34;time&#34;&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;overlaytext&#34; style=&#34;right:20px;left:20px;top:200px;color:#eeff66;text-align:right;font-size:38px&#34;&gt;How to Be an Extraordinary Teacher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For tenure-track professors at research-focused universities, teaching
is not considered an important part of your job.  So long as you don&amp;rsquo;t
do so badly to engender a stream of complaints to your dean, being a
mediocre teacher is unlikely to harm your tenure case; even if you are a
spectaular teacher, it won&amp;rsquo;t help make up for weaknesses in your
research record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs1120-f11/all/2011/class-41-the-cake-of-computing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/cake-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34; alt=&#34;cake&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if the only thing that matters to you is getting tenure, you should
aim to teach at a level just above the &amp;ldquo;threshold of embarrassment&amp;rdquo;, and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/evans/paradise/research/&#34;&gt;skip the rest of this section&lt;/a&gt;.  Hopefully,
however, you came to a university because you want to teach, and will
find teaching to be the most rewarding, fulfilling, and impactful aspect
of your career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren&amp;rsquo;t sure if you find teaching gratifying yet, its worth
putting in the energy to be an extraordinary teacher at least once to
discover if you do.  I&amp;rsquo;ve seen too many new faculty start their
tenure-track positions overly stressed out about getting research
funding and being advised not to spend too much time teaching. This
inevitably leads to a bad first teaching experience, and the victims
concluding that they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t care about teaching but instead should
treat it as a necessary burden of their faculty position.  If you find
you really don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy teaching enough to want to do it well, you&amp;rsquo;d be
much better off finding a position that does not expect you to teach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-teach-extraordinarily:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb&#34;&gt;How to Teach Extraordinarily&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that the standards of teaching in US universities are
so low in general, that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take much to be extraordinary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two simple steps are enough to get over that threshold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respect your &lt;strong&gt;students&amp;rsquo; time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on how you want to impact students &lt;strong&gt;five years from now&lt;/strong&gt;, not
on what they can do sitting on an uncomfortable chair for a few hours at
the end of the semester.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most other things follow from these two premises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-and-why-to-respect-students-time:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb&#34;&gt;How (and Why) to Respect Students&amp;rsquo; Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respecting students should go without saying (or at least, it is said
frequently enough to be &amp;ldquo;consensus advice&amp;rdquo;), but the key to respecting
people is &lt;em&gt;respecting their time&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power imbalance between faculty and students leads to many faculty
behaving in ways that are tremendously disrespectful of students&amp;rsquo; time
and getting away with it.  Sometimes professors seem to intentionally do
things to waste students&amp;rsquo; time just to clarify how powerful and
important they are.  This is cruel and misguided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Come to Class Early.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve observed many classes where the professor
  arrives a few minutes after the scheduled class time, fumbles around
  hooking up a laptop to a projector, searches for some slides to
  display, and finally gets class started several minutes late.
  Expecting dozens of students to sit around for several minutes waiting
  for class to start is not respectful of their time, and sends the
  dangerous message that you don&amp;rsquo;t think class time is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End Class On-Time (or Early).&lt;/strong&gt; Going over the scheduled end-time is
  less bad than arriving too late to start on time, but similarly
  disrespectful of students&amp;rsquo; time.  The way to end on time isn&amp;rsquo;t to rush
  through whatever you thought you would cover that day to get to the
  end as you planned.  Instead, if you notice time is running low, &lt;em&gt;slow
  down&lt;/em&gt;, find a reasonable place to stop before class time expires, and
  ask for questions.  I&amp;rsquo;ve never heard anyone complain when a lecture or
  talk ends a bit early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Assign Busywork.&lt;/strong&gt; The point of assignments is to provide good
  conditions for students to learn interesting, valuable, and important
  things.  Don&amp;rsquo;t assign tasks just to have something to grade.  Be
  flexible in your assignments, so students for whom the standard
  assignment would not be worthwhile can do something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/balletclass.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Be Oblivious.&lt;/strong&gt; I took my two-year old daughter to a ballet
  class recently where the teacher started by telling us about her
  illustrious ballet career and then tried to teach the toddlers the
  ballet positions and have them follow complex directions holding onto
  a barre.  She was completely oblivious to the obvious fact that none
  of the toddlers were paying any attention to this and just wanted to
  run around, spinning in their tutus.  As a university teacher, your
  students are not nearly as good as the toddlers in providing immediate
  and clear feedback when what you are doing isn&amp;rsquo;t appropriate.  But,
  they still provide fairly clear signs when things are off, and (unlike
  the toddlers) you can always stop and ask them what&amp;rsquo;s wrong if it
  seems like no one is getting it.  If you don&amp;rsquo;t get a useful response,
  maybe they are just tired, so ask them to stand up and move around
  (this works, even in large classes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spend a Ridiculous Amount of Time Preparing Lectures.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The
  consensus advice (which I heard from many people, but also find
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://americanfacultyassociation.blogspot.com/2012/02/hours-for-teaching-and-preparation-rule.html&#34;&gt;written
  down&lt;/a&gt;)
  is to spend about 2 hours of preparation time for each hour of class
  time.  This is probably good advice if your goal is to be squarely in
  the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/evans/paradise/time/#how-to-be-mediocre-not:eefdcd66b28c2b86ef84bba398f2d59a&#34;&gt;trough of mediocrity&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (and, probably
  wasting time, since a lecture you spent 15-60 minutes preparing would
  probably get over the embarrassment threshold, and may well be better
  than the one you spend 2 hours preparing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There may be some people who can prepare great lectures that quickly,
  but I have never been able to (and I hear similar things from everyone
  I know of who does great lectures).  I find that I need at least 10
  hours to prepare a new lecture I&amp;rsquo;m not embarrassed by, and often 20-30
  hours to prepare one I consider good.  I find time spent preparing a
  lecture, especially on a topic that I don&amp;rsquo;t already know much about,
  to be very fun and worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to feel guilty about spending
  too much time preparing lectures, and was frequently told it was
  foolish to do this, but have concluded that spending sufficient time
  to prepare lectures that I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with is justified not just for
  selfish reasons of personal pride.  One way to justify it, at least in
  larger classes, is to divide your preparation time by the number of
  students in the class.  Spending 10 hours to prepare a lecture for a
  100-person class seems much more reasonable when viewed as 6 minutes
  per student.  &lt;A href=&#34;http://www.jeffersonswheel.org/2009/hacking-the-world-cup-draw&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/nytsports.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  It gets better if you amortize the cost of multiple iterations of the
  same course; it still takes quite a bit of time to prepare to &amp;ldquo;reuse&amp;rdquo;
  an old lecture (with improvements and adaptations), but a lot less
  than the time to prepare a new lecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional justification comes from making materials you prepare for
  your lectures available to an audience beyond just your class.  Many
  gratifying and unexpected things can come from this, ranging from
  other faculty finding and adapting your course materials to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jeffersonswheel.org/2009/hacking-the-world-cup-draw&#34;&gt;achieving
  your lifelong dream of making the sports pages of the &lt;em&gt;New York
  Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, aside from satisfying my own curiousty, it is also the case
  that I often get research ideas when preparing lectures on topics far
  afield from my normal research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I won&amp;rsquo;t include anything here about actually developing lectures, but I
agree with most of the advice from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/metatalk/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meta Talk: How to Give a Talk So
Good You&amp;rsquo;ll Be Asked to Give Talks About
Nothing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-have-long-term-impact:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb&#34;&gt;How to Have Long-Term Impact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your goal is to just teach mediocre classes that get across some
material to your students, you should consider if your time would be
more effectively spent by holding office hours during the time you would
spend preparing and giving mediocre lectures, and encouring the students
to read and watch recorded classes rather than being bored in class.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, you do want to be an extraordinary teacher, and that means
doing things that aim to have a more significant and longer term impact
on your students and the world beyond.  Achieving this is very rare, and
I can&amp;rsquo;t claim to have a high success rate on this, but it is still worth
aspiring to since when it actually works out it is the most rewarding
and fulfilling thing you can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/babymusicclass.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Aspire to be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/talks/smoochs/&#34;&gt;more like baby music
  class&lt;/a&gt; than a
  typical university lecture.&lt;/strong&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t fall for all the hype about
  &amp;ldquo;active learning&amp;rdquo; and end up wasting most of class time with low-value
  activities, but realize that the traditional lecture model is a very
  challenging learning environment for most people.  Find ways to get
  students to move around, learn from each other, have fun, and work
  within students&amp;rsquo; actual attention spans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Teach to the &amp;ldquo;Middle&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/strong&gt; Teaching to the middle gives everyone a
  mediocre experience.  You should aim to construct classes in a way
  that ensures everyone in the class gets the most important, biggest
  ideas, and that even the most advanced students are challenged by
  something every class.  One of the main challenges you face as a
  university teacher is finding a way to avoid losing or overwhelming
  the least advanced students, without making things boring for the most
  advanced ones.  Targeting the middle is the worst solution to this,
  serving no one in the class well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bring the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs1120-f11/all/2011/class-9-consistent-hashing&#34;&gt;W&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/DavidEvansUVa/lecture20-10905488&#34;&gt;o&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iA6AYtmJ4UI&#34;&gt;r&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/DavidEvansUVa/lecture27-10905505&#34;&gt;l&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rust-class.org/class-23-invent-the-future.html&#34;&gt;d&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://rust-class.org/0/class-17-trick-or-treat-protocols.html&#34;&gt;into&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://rust-class.org/0/class-3-zero-to-a-billion-in-486-years.html&#34;&gt;Your&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs201j-fall2002/lectures/lecture23.ppt&#34;&gt;Class&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs1120-f09/classes/class18/lecture18.pdf&#34;&gt;room&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Bring Your &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs200-spring2003/poolside/&#34;&gt;Classroom&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs588-fall2001/problem-sets/ps4-selected.html&#34;&gt;into&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs3102/?page_id=324&#34;&gt;Wo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs200-spring2004/&#34;&gt;r&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/cs2220/?p=417&#34;&gt;l&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs1120-f11/conveying-computing-highlights&#34;&gt;d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-grade:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb&#34;&gt;How to Grade&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many professors spend a huge amount of time and stress on grading.  I
can think of few things less worthwhile to spend time on, but many
faculty fall into the trap of responding to student complaints about
grading being vague or unfair by adopting increasing painstaking and
demoralizing grading rubrics and complicated &amp;ldquo;regrading&amp;rdquo; protocols for
students and professors to spend time quibbling over points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of grading is to provide students with useful feedback, not to
allocate and deduct points for trivial things.  There is no need to
grade every question, or figure out a detailed points-based grading
rubric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend this simple &amp;ldquo;gold-star&amp;rdquo; grading scale for most assignments: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theonion.com/articles/bush-earmarks-15-billion-gold-stars-for-education,392/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/onion.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34; border=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;gold stars&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Meaning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;font size=&#34;+1&#34; color=&#34;gold&#34;&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Excellent work&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;font size=&#34;+1&#34; color=&#34;green&#34;&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Got what you should out of this&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;font size=&#34;+1&#34; color=&#34;silver&#34;&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Decent effort, but some serious problems&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inevitably, someone will ask what the &amp;ldquo;average&amp;rdquo; on an assignment was.&lt;br /&gt;
It should be a murky goldish-greenish-silver star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to limit expectations, though, so the top of the scale is unbounded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Stars&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Meaning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;+1&#34; color=&#34;gold&#34;&gt;&amp;#9733;&amp;#9733;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Exceptional!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;+1&#34; color=&#34;gold&#34;&gt;&amp;#9733;&amp;#9733;&amp;#9733;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Better than I though possible.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;+1&#34; color=&#34;gold&#34;&gt;&amp;#9733;&amp;#9733;&amp;#9733;&amp;#9733;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;True breakthrough!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;+1&#34; color=&#34;gold&#34;&gt;&amp;#9733;&amp;#9733;&amp;#9733;&amp;#9733;&amp;#9733;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs588-fall2001/manifests/0926.html&#34;&gt;Breakthrough of Gaussian Proportions!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theonion.com/articles/rich-firstgrader-buys-whole-sheet-of-gold-stars,3160/&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;../images/wholesheet.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34; alt=&#34;whole sheet&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Using a simple, star-based grading system will save you from lots of
unnecessary suffering and unpleasantness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are worried that such a system will not provide enough
fine-grained data for you to adequately distinguish the B+, B, and B-
students at the end of the semester, you should reconsider whether or
not it is really so important for you to do that.  These differences
only matter to mediocre companies with misguided hiring practices, and
you should hope your students find more interesting places to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In introductory courses, there are three &amp;ldquo;grades&amp;rdquo; that matter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifying superstar students who you want to recruit to your research group.  (A+ final grade, and letter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sending a signal that students should take more classes in your discipline and consider it as a major. (A)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indicating that a student put forth a reasonable effort, but is likely to find something else better suited to their talents and abilities. (B)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lower grades for cases where students either demonstrated clear incompetence or unacceptable effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more thoughts on grading for more advanced classes, see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rust-class.org/0/pages/course-wrapup.html#grading&#34;&gt;wrapup
for my OS
class&lt;/a&gt;.
If you get any complaints about &amp;ldquo;grade inflation&amp;rdquo;, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20030401140615/http://www.cavalierdaily.com/letters.asp?pid=990&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A new generation of students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-whom-are-you-teaching:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb&#34;&gt;For Whom Are You Teaching?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people think this is a silly question &amp;mdash; obviously, you are teaching
for the students sitting right in front of you.  But, that&amp;rsquo;s the wrong
answer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The students in your class are the most immediate victims or (hopefully)
beneficiaries of your teaching, but, at least if you are a faculty
member at an elite public university&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb:3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, they are not the primary
people you are teaching for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your salary is mostly not paid from those students&amp;rsquo; tuition, and by
being able to attend your university, those students are already in the
lucky (and hopefuly deserving!) elite of society, nearly all of whom
will go on to lucrative and pleasant careers whether or not they took
your class.  The reason countries and states have public universities
(or provide public support to private ones), is not so a handful of
selected students can obtain some vocational training and earn a
recognized credential.  It is so some of those students go on to do
things that make the world a better place for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should, of course, care about your students and want them to be
successful at individuals.  But, keep in mind that your real purpose is
to do things that serve the public at large.  This should predispose you
to make all of your teaching materials open (posted on public websites),
risk trying new things (even if there is some chance it will have
negative consequences for your current students), and invest in things
that will have long-term, external value even when it takes time away
from immediate value for your classroom students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../research&#34; class=&#34;button_accent&#34;&gt;Next:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;How to Be a Remarkable Researcher&amp;nbsp;&amp;rarr;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb:1&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had the luxury of light teaching loads, where I am expected to teach at most one class a semester (and often only expected to teach a small seminar).  This is common for computer science faculty at research-focused universities, but may make my advice here seem unreasonable for someone who has to teach several courses at once.  I have a lot of sympathy for people with such heavy teaching loads, but don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to manage this without making a lot of compromises.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb:2&#34;&gt;Depending on your institution and status, you might risk losing your job if you actually do this.  But, if the reason you are holding class is to avoid losing your job rather than actually provide some benefits to yourself and your students, perhaps it would still be a good risk to do this.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb:3&#34;&gt;Here, &amp;ldquo;elite&amp;rdquo; means any institution where some of the applicants who satisfy some minimal threshold (e.g., have a high school diploma or equivalent) and are willing to pay are rejected.  I expect the same beliefs apply for most private universities, but their missions are less clear and may vary enough for this not to always be true.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:416f445d9bade50adf875443b512ceeb:3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Be a Remarkable Researcher</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/research/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;photohead&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/pictures/za2010/0613-0616_kruger/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;../images/rhino.jpg&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; alt=&#34;rhino&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;overlaytext&#34; style=&#34;right:20px;left:180px;top:-50px;color:#ff3333;text-align:right;font-size:38px&#34;&gt;How to Be a Remarkable Researcher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time you have successfully completed a PhD, you should be
confident in your talents as a researcher.  You should feel comfortable
that you&amp;rsquo;ve developed &lt;strong&gt;good taste&lt;/strong&gt; for selecting research problems,
possess the &lt;strong&gt;tenacity to tackle hard challenges&lt;/strong&gt; and see them through,
have &lt;strong&gt;mastered the important technical aspects&lt;/strong&gt; of your field, and
have &lt;strong&gt;learned to present your work in writing and verbally&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are lacking confidence in those things, you should assume that
the people who hired you were not totally duped and that you are more
capable than you may realize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main new challenges you have as a professor are to &lt;strong&gt;raise
funding&lt;/strong&gt;, to &lt;strong&gt;advise research students&lt;/strong&gt;, and to &lt;strong&gt;avoid getting stuck
in a comfortable rut&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-raise-funds:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40&#34;&gt;How to Raise Funds&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/pin-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34; alt=&#34;PIN&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m putting fund-raising first, not because it is the most important
thing for new faculty, but it is the one thing nearly all new faculty
seem to be most worried about (but shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you will face pressures from your administration to raise as
much money as possible, your actual goal should be to raise &lt;em&gt;enough&lt;/em&gt;
money to be able to support the activities you want, and to raise that
money in ways that impose as little overhead (time spent doing things
you don&amp;rsquo;t want to do) and constraints (lack of freedom in how you use
the funds) as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For US-based researchers, this means funding from the National Science
Foundation and industry gifts.  You should consider any other funding
sources carefully; there are sometimes great opportunites to get funding
from other agencies or non-gift corporate funding, but be wary of the
overhead required.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;read-exemplary-proposals:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40&#34;&gt;Read Exemplary Proposals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;funds&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;./turing.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;rightbar&#34; src=&#34;../images/turing-edit.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; alt=&#34;Turing&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Nearly everyone starts their career as a researcher by reading exemplary
research papers and learning from them what makes a paper great.  Hardly
anyone ever reads exemplary proposals, largely because proposals tend to
be kept secret so it is hard to find ones to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would encourage everyone to at least read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/evans/paradise/turing/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;proposal Alan Turing
and three colleagues at Bletchly Park wrote to Winston
Churchill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to obtain support for cryptanalysis
work during World War II.  (I&amp;rsquo;ve annotated the proposal with some
sidebar comments.)  This is quite different from what is needed for a
typical NSF proposal today, but there is still much to learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding more recent versions of proposals to read is tougher, but you
can read some of mine here (I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t claim that they are &amp;ldquo;exemplary&amp;rdquo;,
but they did get funded; note that some of the specific rules of what
must be in an NSF proposal and how it must be formatted have changed
since these proposals):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Automated Security Testing for Applications Integrating Third-Party Services&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/docs/satc-scan.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;]
 (with Yuchen Zhou (PhD Student); &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rematchr.org/project/1422332&#34;&gt;NSF Secure and Trustworthy Cyberspace 2013&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Practical Secure Two-Party Computation: Techniques, Tools, and Applications&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/docs/mpc.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;]
 (with Yan Huang (PhD Student), Aaron Mackey, abhi shelat, Michael Hicks, Jonathan Katz, Steven Myers; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rematchr.org/project/1111781&#34;&gt;NSF Trustworthy Computing 2011&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Implementable Privacy and Security for Resource-Constrained Devices&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/docs/implementablesecurity-packaged.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;]
 (with Karsten Nohl (PhD Student), Benton Calhoun, John Lach, and abhi shelat; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rematchr.org/project/0831426&#34;&gt;NSF Trustworthy Computing 2008&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Programming the Swarm&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/docs/career.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;]
 (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rematchr.org/project/0092945&#34;&gt;NSF CAREER 2000&lt;/a&gt;) (This is very far from being a model proposal, but it did somehow get funded.  It was the first proposal I wrote, and gives some idea of how far outside one&amp;rsquo;s previous work a CAREER proposal can be.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;write-fewer-proposals:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40&#34;&gt;Write Fewer Proposals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many new faculty seem to get the advice (especially from adminstrators
who benefit from their funding overhead charges!) to go after as many
funding opportunities as they can, and I&amp;rsquo;ve known of new faculty who
submit over a dozen proposals a year (and one who bragged of submitting
over 100 proposals before going up for tenure!), including from low
quality funding sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/pictures/seattle/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/grumpyreviewer.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Sometimes this advice is given by well-meaning individuals who point to
low acceptance rates from NSF, and encourage faculty to submit lots of
proposals to hope one or two get lucky.  This would make sense if the
review process was really arbitrary, but its not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NSF&amp;rsquo;s proposal review process is done by panels of faculty recruited by
the Program Manager.  These reviewers (for the most part) take it very
seriously and have substantive discussions about the content of
proposals to decide what to recommend for funding.  Most panels meet for
an in-person two-day meeting in Arlington, although teleconference
panels are occasionaly used.  The panel reaches a consensus, and makes a
recommendation to the Program Manager, who then makes a recommendation
up the chain for which proposals should be funded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my experience (as both a submitter and panelist), at least, this
process works remarkably well.  In retrospect, think the correct
decision has been made for nearly every proposal I&amp;rsquo;ve submitted in the
past 10 years, and although I have sometimes disagreed with
recommendations made by a panel I&amp;rsquo;ve been on, all but one (of about 15
panels I&amp;rsquo;ve been on) worked well and made decisions based on substantive
analysis of the merits of submitted proposals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are being advised to submit lots of proposals because of low
acceptance rates reported for NSF programs, the correct response is to
submit fewer proposals, and to put better ideas and more effort into
each one to ensure it has a high likelihood of being funded.  Don&amp;rsquo;t
submit a lot of proposals because you want to look productive (or are
told that&amp;rsquo;s what you should do to be productive), or because you think
funding decisions are mostly arbitrary so your chances are maximized by
sending off lots of mediocre proposals.
   &lt;div class=&#34;rightnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;In writing proposals to prospective clients, be sure to clearly state the benefits they will receive:
&lt;b&gt;WRONG:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;I sincerely believe that it is to your advantage to accept this
proposal.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;b&gt;RIGHT:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;I have photographs of you naked with a squirrel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miamiherald.com/living/liv-columns-blogs/dave-barry/article1928613.html&#34;&gt;Dave Barry&amp;rsquo;s advice of writing proposals&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NSF funding decisions are much less random that those from even the best
program committees, and it is much better to submit one or two good
proposals a year than to try writing many mediocre ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-useful-feedback:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40&#34;&gt;Get Useful Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of writing fewer proposals is to have more time to get useful
feedback on each proposal before it is submitted.  Getting feedback
before submission is especially important for your first few proposals,
but even as an experienced proposal-writer, it is useful to see how well
your ideas come across in the proposal to someone unfamiliar with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t expect to get useful feedback from the actual reviews.  By the
time you get these, it will be at least six months after you submitted
the proposal, and they will be watered down to the point where it is
hard to know what the reviewers really felt.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get useful feedback, you need to have a fairly complete draft of the
proposal ready well before the deadline and get a colleague to read it
critically.  This needs to be done at least two weeks before the
deadline to give the reader enough time to read it, and leave enough
time for you to make substantial revisions in response (and possibly
even run the revised version by the reader before submission).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, you have someone who can provide useful feedback to you on
your proposals.  If you&amp;rsquo;ve read this far and have a fairly complete
proposal ready at least two weeks before the deadline, though, I&amp;rsquo;m happy
to provide feedback on it (but may be of limited help depending on how
close you are to areas I know something about).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-and-why-to-advise:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40&#34;&gt;How (and Why) to Advise&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following a world cup qualifying vicotory where two players he developed
for the national team subbed into the game and performed well, a
reporter asked coach J&amp;uuml;rgen Klinsmann whether he was &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;lucky&lt;/em&gt; or
&lt;em&gt;brilliant&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.  His answer was that he felt &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;proud&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;.  The biggest
reward you get as an advisor is when you can feel proud of your student,
and you get to do this no matter if you were brilliant or lucky!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge you have as a new professor is that your
experience with research advising is probably limited to what you
experienced with your own PhD advisor (and perhaps a few other research
supervisors).  This is hopefully a good and valuable experience, but you
should be wary of thinking you know how to advise students by doing what
your advisor did for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You were a unique and exceptional student, so the way your advisor
advised you is almost certainly the wrong way for you to advise your
students!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nano-manage-or-deci-manage-but-never-micro-manage:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40&#34;&gt;Nano-manage or Deci-manage, but never Micro-manage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing you need to decide is how much freedom you want do give
your students.  Ideally, all of your students will be brilliant, wise,
self-motivated, and posessing uncanny judgement.  For such students,
&lt;em&gt;deci-management&lt;/em&gt; is the best option.  Provide a few pointers to things
that you think are interesting, give feedback on the ideas the student
comes up with, and help with the finer points of how to present the work
effectively.  But, otherwise, give the student as much space and little
management as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other situations, &lt;em&gt;nano-management&lt;/em&gt; may be better.  This means
working closely with the student, perhaps even working together on part
of a project (for me, this is most common with writing, but can be
appropriate for design and programming also).  It is very worthwhile to
go through work in great detail, providing feedback and suggestions at a
low-level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most students, a mix of deci-management and nano-management is best.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know of any students for whom deci-management was the best
approach for their entire PhD process, and any student who needs to be
nano-managed for more than a few short periods during their PhDship is
probably better off pursuing a different career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micro-management is the worst possible strategy.  It gives the managee
so much direction that they are left with no opportunity for creativity
or (positive) surprise, but not enough direction to make the likelihood
of failure low and not enough collaboration to be a good learning
experience.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone enjoys being micromanaged, and if you
enjoy being a micromanager you should find a job at a large, established
company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your aim as an advisor should be to develop your students into research
leaders.  This means by the time they graduate they have the ability and
confidence needed to identify good problems to work on on their own and
can carry out all aspects of doing the research, including presenting
it.  If you micromanage your students, they may be more productive and
appear more successful, but won&amp;rsquo;t develop what they need to succeed as
an independent research leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-avoid-ruts:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40&#34;&gt;How to Avoid Ruts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may be strange to focus on avoiding ruts in advice for new faculty
members, but falling into a rut is one of the main dangers you face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most comfortable thing to do as a new professor is to keep working
on the same kinds of things you did for your dissertation, and its easy
and common to fall into the trap of spending your whole career doing
essentially the same thing over and over.  For some people, this may be
the right decision.  There are many researchers who I greatly respect
who have devoted their full careers to one problem and developed a line
of research that was a sustained effort in a consistent direction to
tackle that problem.  If you are convinced that the problem you are
working on is the most interesting one, and that the approach you take
is the best way you can contribute to it, its fine to spend your whole
career focused in that way.  But, this should be a conscious decision,
not something you fall into accidentally by just making a series of
&amp;ldquo;comfortable&amp;rdquo; decisions until it is too hard to try something different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;rightnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Reward a person for doing something, and they&amp;rsquo;ll want to keep doing
it. If the reward continues for long enough, they&amp;rsquo;ll keep doing that
thing indefinitely unless something stops them.  This is pretty simple
stuff. Of course, anyone would want to keep doing something that they&amp;rsquo;re
rewarded for. That might take the form of money, praise, social status,
power, impressive-sounding titles, or many other things. But if the
rewards keep flowing without interruption, we can end up like the rat
that keeps pressing a lever in some laboratory &amp;mdash; repetitive and
dull. And it&amp;rsquo;s worth keeping in mind that just because you happen to be
very, very good at pressing that lever, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make you an
interesting rat. You&amp;rsquo;re just a dull rat with one, highly specialized
skill.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://zacharyernst.blogspot.com/2013/12/failure-and-boredom.html&#34;&gt;Zachary Ernst&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switch Areas Frequently.&lt;/strong&gt; For most researchers, the best course is to
find new areas that you find interesting, and which you can bring a
different perspective to.  If you work on the same problems with similar
background and perspective as everyone else, the only way you can do
something significant is if you are smarter, harder-working, and luckier
than others.  Changing focus is uncomfortable though &amp;mdash; working in
a new area requires abandoning all the experience and knowledge you have
in your current area and learning about something new.  The good news in
computer science, at least, is that our field is immature enough that in
most areas it only takes a few months to get sufficiently up-to-speed to
start making research contributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also beneficial if you can vary the problems and approaches you
take without needing to abandon your research community (where a
research community is mostly defined by a set of conferences that
attract a common group of people).  As a new professor, it is important
that you build your reputation and get to know a core group of people in
a particular research community.  One of the great things about being in
the security and privacy research community is that you can work in
almost all areas of computer science without being disconnected from a
primary research community.  This is probably harder in other research
communities, but not impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be First or Last.&lt;/strong&gt; Aim to write either the &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; paper on &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt;, or
  the &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt; paper on &lt;em&gt;Z&lt;/em&gt;.  You&amp;rsquo;ll have a lot more impact by doing this,
  than by writing the 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt;, 26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 87&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;,
  and 193&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; papers on some well-studied topic.  If you find
  yourself working in an area that is so crowded, you more worried about
  getting scooped by someone else doing the same thing, its time to
  switch areas.  Much better to be working on something where you are
  happy to find one or two like-minded colleagues to collaborate with,
  than something where you feel the need to be secretive about your
  latest incremental advance for fear that others are doing something
  similar and you are in a race to publish first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find and Empower Creative Students.&lt;/strong&gt; One of the best ways to avoid
  getting stuck in ruts, is to ensure that you keep working with new
  people who bring different ideas and perspectives from your own.
  Collaborations with other professors and senior researchers can do
  this, but (at least in my experience) such collaborations are very
  difficult beyond efforts to write funding proposals except when they
  are driven by a student.  The best way to continually refresh your
  research is to allow students to drive you into new areas.  Don&amp;rsquo;t be
  afraid to let students work on things you don&amp;rsquo;t know much about, just
  expect them to enough to convince you it is worthwhile and
  interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../video&#34; class=&#34;button_accent&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt; 
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;a href=&#34;../others&#34; class=&#34;button_accent&#34;&gt;Others&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40:1&#34;&gt;DARPA programs typically require PIs to attend at least four PI meetings every year, some as many as six), reports (e.g., some funding requires monthly reports), and constraints (e.g., many DoD awards require strict adherance to a &amp;ldquo;Statement of Work&amp;rdquo;, and the people who check-off that you do what is on that list tend to not be researchers so are not easy to convince that a new idea is better than what was originally proposed).  This is why research groups (and companies) that fall into the trap of taking such funding, end up spending most of their effort managing DARPA, rather than actually doing research.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40:2&#34;&gt;At the end of an NSF panel, all the panelists go through all the reviews and review summaries, and any verbiage that might be deemed negative is toned down.  This is good for avoiding hurt feelings, but usually means the most useful advice to the proposer is removed or obfuscated before the reviewers are sent back.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:42f623b3bad309d5d6619d450af47d40:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turing&#39;s Proposal</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/turing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/turing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;letter-to-winson-churchill:dfc7493873bf2f3334158ec44e84faab&#34;&gt;Letter to Winson Churchill&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
   Transcribed from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.maths.ed.ac.uk/~aar/turingletter.pdf&#34;&gt;Jack Copeland&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Essential Turing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
   &lt;/center&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/pictures/bletchley/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;rightbar12&#34; src=&#34;../images/hut-edit.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; alt=&#34;Hut 6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Secret and Confidential&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Prime Minister only&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
   &lt;b&gt;Hut 6 and Hut 8&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
   21st October 1941&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;Dear Prime Minister,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;rightbar12&#34;&gt;
   &lt;strong&gt;Know your audience.&lt;/strong&gt; Turing&amp;rsquo;s audience is
Prime Minister Churchill.  Yours is less well defined, but not entirely
unknown.  For NSF proposals, you are writing for a mix of &lt;em&gt;diligent,
competent&lt;/em&gt; reviewers and &lt;em&gt;lazy, negative&lt;/em&gt; ones.  You should aim to write proposals that appeal to both types of reviewers.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
Some weeks ago you paid us the honour of a visit, and we believe that
you regard our work as important. You will have seen that, thanks
largely to the energy and foresight of Commander Travis, we have been
well supplied with the ‘bombes’ for the breaking of the German Enigma
codes. We think, however, that you ought to know that this work is being
held up, and in some cases is not being done at all, principally because
we cannot get sufficient staff to deal with it. Our reason for writing
to you direct is that for months we have done everything that we
possibly can through the normal channels, and that we despair of any
early improvement without your intervention. No doubt in the long run
these particular requirements will be met, but meanwhile still more
precious months will have been wasted, and as our needs are continually
expanding we see little hope of ever being adequately staffed.&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;rightbar12&#34;&gt;
   You are competing for limited resources, so need to make the case that your project will provide more benefits relative to its cost than other projects. This depends on both making that case that the &lt;strong&gt;problem you are working on is important&lt;/strong&gt;, and that you have a &lt;strong&gt;unique approach which is likely to produce valuable results&lt;/strong&gt;.
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
We realise that there is a tremendous demand for labour of all kinds and
that its allocation is a matter of priorities. The trouble to our mind
is that as we are a very small section with numerically trivial
requirements it is very difficult to bring home to the authorities
finally responsible either the importance of what is done here or the
urgent necessity of dealing promptly with our requests. At the same time
we find it hard to believe that it is really impossible to produce
quickly the additional staff that we need, even if this meant
interfering with the normal machinery of allocations.&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;rightbar12&#34;&gt;
   &lt;strong&gt;Be consise&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;get to the point quickly!&lt;/strong&gt;  It should not be a challenge for reviewers to figure out what you are proposing to do.
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
We do not wish to burden you with a detailed list of our difficulties,
but the following are the bottlenecks which are causing us the most
acute anxiety.
   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-class-typewriterbig-1-breaking-of-naval-enigma-hut-8-span:dfc7493873bf2f3334158ec44e84faab&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;typewriterbig&#34;&gt;1. Breaking of Naval Enigma (Hut 8)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
Owing to shortage of staff and the overworking of his present team the
Hollerith section here under Mr Freeborn has had to stop working night
shifts. The effect of this is that the finding of the naval keys is
being delayed at least twelve hours every day. In order to enable him to
start night shifts again Freeborn needs immediately about twenty more
untrained Grade III women clerks. To put himself in a really adequate
position to deal with any likely demands he will want a good many more.
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;rightbar12&#34;&gt;
   This reads disturbingly sexist to modern ears, but keep in mind that is was written in 1941.  In your writing (both in proposals and anywhere else), you should work hard to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs655/readings/purity.html&#34;&gt;avoid any sexist language&lt;/a&gt;, including use of generic male pronouns.
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
A further serious danger now threatening us is that some of the skilled
male staff, both with the British Tabulating Company at Letchworth and
in Freeborn’s section here, who have so far been exempt from military
service, are now liable to be called up.&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-class-typewriterbig-2-military-and-air-force-enigma-hut-6-span:dfc7493873bf2f3334158ec44e84faab&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;typewriterbig&#34;&gt;2. Military and Air Force Enigma (Hut 6) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
We are intercepting quite a substantial proportion of wireless traffic
in the Middle East which cannot be picked up by our intercepting
stations here. This contains among other things a good deal of new
‘Light Blue’ intelligence. Owing to shortage of trained typists,
however, and the fatigue of our present decoding staff, we cannot get
all this traffic decoded. This has been the state of affairs since
May. Yet all that we need to put matters right is about twenty trained
typists.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-class-typewriterbig-3-bombe-testing-hut-6-and-hut-8-span:dfc7493873bf2f3334158ec44e84faab&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;typewriterbig&#34;&gt;3. Bombe testing, Hut 6 and Hut 8 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;rightbar12&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;WRNS&lt;/em&gt; is the &lt;em&gt;Women&amp;rsquo;s Royal Naval Service&lt;/em&gt;.
The WRNS did much of the clerical work for codebreaking at Bletchley
Park, but many also became (arguably) the first system administrators
and computer programmers, configuring Turing&amp;rsquo;s Bombes and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/cs1120-f11/problem-sets/problem-set-4-constructing-colossi&#34;&gt;Colossus&lt;/a&gt; for different codebreaking programs.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
In July we were promised that the testing of the ‘stories’ produced by
the bombes would be taken over by the WRNS in the bombe hut and that
sufficient WRNS would be provided for this purpose. It is now late in
October and nothing has been done. We do not wish to stress this so
strongly as the two preceding points, because it has not actually
delayed us in delivering the goods. It has, however, meant that staff in
Huts 6 and 8 who are needed for other jobs have had to do the testing
themselves. We cannot help feeling that with a Service matter of this
kind it should have been possible to detail a body of WRNS for this
purpose, if sufficiently urgent instructions had been sent to the right
quarters.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-class-typewriterbig-4-span:dfc7493873bf2f3334158ec44e84faab&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;typewriterbig&#34;&gt;4.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
Apart altogether from staff matters, there are a number of other
directions in which it seems to us that we have met with unnecessary
impediments. It would take too long to set these out in full, and we
realise that some of the matters involved are controversial. The
cumulative effect, however, has been to drive us to the conviction that
the importance of the work is not being impressed with sufficient force
upon those outside authorities with whom we have to deal.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;rightbar12&#34;&gt;
Unlike Turing&amp;rsquo;s, your proposals should not include any whining like this.  But, they should conclude with a clear impact summary, explaining the value that will come from funding your project.
   &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
We have written this letter entirely on our own initiative. We do not
know who or what is responsible for our difficulties, and most
emphatically we do not want to be taken as criticising Commander Travis
who has all along done his utmost to help us in every possible way. But
if we are to do our job as well as it could and should be done it is
absolutely vital that our wants, small as they are, should be promptly
attended to. We have felt that we should be failing in our duty if we
did not draw your attention to the facts and to the effects which they
are having and must continue to have on our work, unless immediate
action is taken.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;rightbar12&#34;&gt;Such obsequieousness is appropriate for certain DoD program managers, but not in NSF proposals!&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;p align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
   We are, Sir, Your obedient servants,&lt;br /&gt;
   A M Turing&lt;br /&gt;
   W G Welchman&lt;br /&gt;
   C H O’D Alexander&lt;br /&gt;
   P S Milner-Barry
   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;churchill-s-response:dfc7493873bf2f3334158ec44e84faab&#34;&gt;Churchill&amp;rsquo;s Response&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/actionthisday.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; class=&#34;rightbar&#34;&gt;
   &lt;span class=&#34;typewriter&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Action this day.&lt;/strong&gt;  Make sure they have all they want on extreme priority
and report to me that this had been done.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../research#how-to-raise-funds&#34; class=&#34;button_accent&#34;&gt;Return:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Research&amp;nbsp;&amp;rarr;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;wide&#34;&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
Video and Slides from &lt;a
href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity14/birds-feather-sessions#colloquium&#34;&gt;USENIX
Security 2014 Doctoral Colloquium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity14/summit-program/presentation/how-live-paradise-pearls-wisdom-new-and&#34;&gt;USENIX Site&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br&gt;
21 August 2014
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;video src=&#34;https://2459d6dc103cb5933875-c0245c5c937c5dedcca3f1764ecc9b2f.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/sec14/evans.mp4&#34; controls width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/38542788&#34;
width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;635&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; border=4
marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

   &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curated Advice from Others</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/others/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-other-advice-pages:77923aeb530cb6e499cb0ad0da0096f1&#34;&gt;My Other Advice Pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/advice/prospective.html&#34;&gt;Advice for Prospective Research Students on Contacting Potential Advisors&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;icomment&#34;&gt;
Mostly not relevant for new faculty, but you may want to have a similar
page with your suggestions for students to contact you.  It saves a lot
of time to be able to point people who send you emails to a URL.  (This
is actually the most visited page on my personal website, getting
several thousand visits a month.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/talks/metatalk/&#34;&gt;Advice on Giving Talks&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;icomment&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest things about becoming a professor is it gets much
harder to get any real feedback on talks (unlike your students, who
should be frequently giving talks and getting a lot of feedback from you
on them).  If you can find a mentor who can give you useful feedback on
talks (including lectures), you are very lucky and should take advantage
of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/advice&#34;&gt;Collected Advice for Students&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;icomment&#34;&gt;
Some of what is collected there is duplicated here, but the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indiana.edu/~kruschke/lab/tipping.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Academic Tipping Guidelines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; only apply to students.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;advice-for-new-faculty:77923aeb530cb6e499cb0ad0da0096f1&#34;&gt;Advice for New Faculty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This essay was largely inspired by Radhika Nagpal&amp;rsquo;s excellent essay
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.scientificamerican.com/guest-blog/2013/07/21/the-awesomest-7-year-postdoc-or-how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-love-the-tenure-track-faculty-life/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Awesomest 7-Year Postdoc or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and
Love the Tenure-Track Faculty
Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a post-doc, though, and believe most post-docs are very far
from paradise, so have a somewhat different perspective than she does
(although we were classmates as undergraduates!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;research:77923aeb530cb6e499cb0ad0da0096f1&#34;&gt;Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard Hamming&amp;rsquo;s advice on doing great research: &lt;a
href=&#34;http://www.paulgraham.com/hamming.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;You and Your
Research&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Talk at Bellcore, 7 March 1986)
   &lt;div class=&#34;excerpt&#34;&gt;
Over on the other side of the dining hall was a chemistry table. I had
worked with one of the fellows, Dave McCall; furthermore he was courting
our secretary at the time. I went over and said, &amp;ldquo;Do you mind if I join
you?&amp;rdquo; They can&amp;rsquo;t say no, so I started eating with them for a while. And
I started asking, &amp;ldquo;What are the important problems of your field?&amp;rdquo; And
after a week or so, &amp;ldquo;What important problems are you working on?&amp;rdquo; And
after some more time I came in one day and said, &amp;ldquo;If what you are doing
is not important, and if you don&amp;rsquo;t think it is going to lead to
something important, why are you at Bell Labs working on it?&amp;rdquo; I wasn&amp;rsquo;t
welcomed after that; I had to find somebody else to eat with!&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not work on an important problem, it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely you&amp;rsquo;ll do
important work&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;rightnote&#34;&gt;
This line is frequently quoted (included in &lt;a
href=&#34;http://gradschool.unc.edu/events/hooding/2012/&#34;&gt;Levoy&amp;rsquo;s talk&lt;/a&gt;),
and seems obviously right, but I think its wrong and dangerous!  Much
better to work on obviously fun problems, than obviously important
ones.  See &lt;a
href=&#34;http://scienceblogs.com/thescian/2008/03/11/what-are-worthwhile-problems-f/&#34;&gt;Richard
Feynman&amp;rsquo;s letter to Koichi Mano&lt;/a&gt; for a better perspective on this.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marc Levoy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://gradschool.unc.edu/events/hooding/2012/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where do
 disruptive ideas come from?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (hooding ceremony speech at the
 University of North Carolina)
   &lt;div class=&#34;excerpt&#34;&gt;
For three years I lived next door to Facebook. Literally next door. I
 could throw a rock from my bedroom window and break a window in Mark
 Zuckerberg&amp;rsquo;s office. They have a particular culture at Facebook: young,
 edgy, in-your-face. Their walls are covered with graffiti and posters,
 spray-painted in Wild West Wanted-dead-or-alive font. One of them says:
 &amp;ldquo;Move fast, break things.&amp;rdquo;  Their offices have concrete floors, no
 interior walls and lots of skateboards, so I imagine they do break
 things.  My favorite poster says, &amp;ldquo;What would you do if you weren&amp;rsquo;t
 afraid?&amp;rdquo;  Being afraid is useful. On the savannah it kept us from being
 eaten by lions. Nevertheless, this is the message I&amp;rsquo;d like to leave you
 with, the same message my mentor Don Greenberg gave to me. Know your
 fears, know also what you really want, weigh the odds, and
 occasionally, make a run for it.&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bme.virginia.edu/people/schwartz.php&#34;&gt;Martin Schwartz&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; &lt;a
href=&#34;http://jcs.biologists.org/content/121/11/1771.full&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The
importance of stupidity in scientific research&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;excerpt&#34;&gt;
We don&amp;rsquo;t do a good enough job of teaching our students how to be
productively stupid &amp;mdash; that is, if we don&amp;rsquo;t feel stupid it means
we&amp;rsquo;re not really trying.
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;writing:77923aeb530cb6e499cb0ad0da0096f1&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marc Raibert&amp;rsquo;s advice on &lt;a
href=&#34;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~pausch/Randy/Randy/raibert.htm&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Good Writing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;excerpt&#34;&gt;
My formula for good writing is simple: once you decide that you want to
produce good writing and that you can produce good writing, then all
that remains is to write bad stuff, and to revise the bad stuff until it
is good.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Pinker&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a
href=&#34;http://chronicle.com/article/Why-Academics-Writing-Stinks/148989/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why
Academics&amp;rsquo; Writing Stinks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;pinker.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF with more commentary&lt;/a&gt;]
   &lt;div class=&#34;excerpt&#34;&gt;
Academics mindlessly cushion their prose with wads of fluff that imply
they are not willing to stand behind what they say. Those include
almost, apparently, comparatively, fairly, in part, nearly, partially,
predominantly, presumably, rather, relatively, seemingly, so to speak,
somewhat, sort of, to a certain degree, to some extent, and the
ubiquitous I would argue. (Does that mean you would argue for your
position if things were different, but are not willing to argue for it now?)
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terence Tao&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a
href=&#34;http://terrytao.wordpress.com/advice-on-writing-papers/&#34;&gt;advice on
writing papers&lt;/a&gt; including &lt;a
href=&#34;http://terrytao.wordpress.com/advice-on-writing-papers/use-the-introduction-to-%E2%80%9Csell%E2%80%9D-the-key-points-of-your-paper/&#34;&gt;introductions&lt;/a&gt;:
   &lt;div class=&#34;excerpt&#34;&gt;
This can be as much the fault of the author as it is of the referee; it
is incumbent on the author to state as clearly as possible what the
merits, novelties, and ramifications of the paper are, and the fact that
an expert in the field could read the introduction and not see these is
a sign that the introduction is not yet of publication quality.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave Barry&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miamiherald.com/living/liv-columns-blogs/dave-barry/article1928613.html&#34;&gt;advice on writing proposals&lt;/a&gt;:
   &lt;div class=&#34;excerpt&#34;&gt;
In writing proposals to prospective
clients, be sure to clearly state the benefits they will receive:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;b&gt;WRONG:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;I sincerely believe that it is to your advantage to accept this
proposal.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;RIGHT:&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ldquo;I have photographs of you naked with a squirrel.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James Altucher&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a
href=&#34;http://www.jamesaltucher.com/2011/03/33-unusual-tips-to-being-a-better-writer/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;33
Unusual Tips to Being a Better Writer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:
   &lt;div class=&#34;excerpt&#34;&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Use a lot of periods.&lt;/b&gt; Forget commas and semicolons. A period makes
people pause. Your sentences should be strong enough that you want
people to pause and think about it.  This will also make your sentences
shorter. Short sentences are good.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geoffrey Pullman&amp;rsquo;s anti-dote to Strunk &amp;amp;
White: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lel.ed.ac.uk/~gpullum/LandOfTheFree.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The
Land of the Free and The Elements of Style&lt;/em&gt; [PDF]&lt;/a&gt;.
   &lt;div class=&#34;excerpt&#34;&gt;
The book&amp;rsquo;s style advice, largely vapid and obvious (&amp;ldquo;Do not overwrite&amp;rdquo;;
&amp;ldquo;Be clear&amp;rdquo;), may do little damage; but the numerous statements about
grammatical correctness are actually harmful. They are riddled with
inaccuracies, uninformed by evidence, and marred by bungled analysis.
Elements is a dogmatic bookful of bad usage advice, and the people who
rely on it have no idea how badly off-beam its grammatical claims are.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greg Mankiw also has some great advice on &lt;a
href=&#34;http://gregmankiw.blogspot.com/2006/10/how-to-write-well.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How
to Write Well&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (a few of the points are specific to economics, since
the advice was written for his staff preparing the Economic Report of
the President, but nearly all of it is good advice for all writing).
(Geoffrey
Pullman &lt;a href=&#34;http://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=18345&#34;&gt;is not a
  fan&lt;/a&gt;, though.)
   &lt;div class=&#34;excerpt&#34;&gt;
The passive voice is avoided by good writers.&lt;br&gt;
The word &amp;ldquo;very&amp;rdquo; is very often very unnecessary.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;teaching:77923aeb530cb6e499cb0ad0da0096f1&#34;&gt;Teaching&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s advice on teaching (focused on teaching mathematics, but
applies to all teaching): &lt;a
href=&#34;http://radian.org/~krstic/LockhartsLament.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s
Lament&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; [PDF]
   &lt;div class=&#34;excerpt&#34;&gt;
Teaching is not about information. It&amp;rsquo;s about having an honest
intellectual relationship with your students. It requires no method, no
tools, and no training. Just the ability to be real. And if you can&amp;rsquo;t be
real, then you have no right to inflict yourself upon innocent children.
&amp;hellip;
It may be true that you have to be able to read in order to fill out
forms at the DMV, but that&amp;rsquo;s not why we teach children to read. We
teach them to read for the higher purpose of allowing them access to
beautiful and meaningful ideas.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;advising:77923aeb530cb6e499cb0ad0da0096f1&#34;&gt;Advising&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey Ullman, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cacm.acm.org/magazines/2009/3/21781-advising-students-for-success/fulltext&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advising Students for
Success&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/comments/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;discussion:03e7713c1e56da666eeab8dfbbf51091&#34;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to post comments here (can be anonymous if you want) or email me directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;disqus_thread&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34;&gt;
/* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
   var disqus_url = &#39;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/paradise/comments&#39;;
   var disqus_shortname = &#39;davidevans&#39;; // required: replace example with your forum shortname

   /* * * DON&#39;T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
   (function() {
            var dsq = document.createElement(&#39;script&#39;); dsq.type = &#39;text/javascript&#39;; dsq.async = true;
            dsq.src = &#39;//&#39; + disqus_shortname + &#39;.disqus.com/embed.js&#39;;
            (document.getElementsByTagName(&#39;head&#39;)[0] ||  document.getElementsByTagName(&#39;body&#39;)[0]).appendChild(dsq);
        })();
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view
    the &lt;a href=&#34;http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&#34;&gt;comments powered by
    Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://disqus.com&#34; class=&#34;dsq-brlink&#34;&gt;Comments powered by &lt;span class=&#34;logo-disqus&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>